const QuestionData = [
  {
    question: 'Who was the first woman Prime Minister of Pakistan?',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Benazir bhutto',
      },
      {option1: 'b', option: 'Sheikh Hasina Wazed'},
      {option1: 'c', option: 'Hina Rabbani Khar'},
      {option1: 'd', option: 'None of Above'},
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Benazir bhutto',
  },
  {
    question:
      'Which among the following is not a neighboring country of Pakistan?',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'China',
      },
      {option: 'Iran'},
      {option: 'Iraq'},
      {option: 'Afghanistan'},
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Iraq',
  },
  {
    question:
      'The famous badshahi mosque is situated in which city in Pakistan?',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lahore',
      },
      {option: 'Karachi'},
      {option: 'Islamabad'},
      {option: 'None of Above'},
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Lahore',
  },
  {
    question: 'Who is known as the ‘mother of the nation’ of Pakistan? ',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Benazir bhutto',
      },
      {option: 'Fatima jinnah'},
      {option: 'Fatima sughra'},
      {option: 'None of Above'},
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Fatima jinnah',
  },
  {
    question: 'What is the rank of Pakistan population-wise',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '9th',
      },
      {option: '5th'},
      {option: '7th'},
      {option: '6th'},
    ],
    correctAnswer: '5th',
  },
];
const firstYear = [
  {
    _id: '6676b15bf11e762e9a863536',
    question:
      'In the reaction 2H₂ + O₂ → 2H₂O, how many grams of water are produced from 4 grams of hydrogen gas (H₂)? (Molar masses: H₂ = 2 g/mol, H₂O = 18 g/mol)',
    correctAnswer: '36 grams',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '18 grams',
      },
      {
        option: '36 grams',
      },
      {
        option: '54 grams',
      },
      {
        option: '72 grams',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b153f11e762e9a863533',
    question:
      'How many moles of hydrogen gas are needed to react with 1 mole of nitrogen gas to form ammonia (N₂ + 3H₂ → 2NH₃)?',
    correctAnswer: '3 moles',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1 mole',
      },
      {
        option: '2 moles',
      },
      {
        option: '3 moles',
      },
      {
        option: '4 moles',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b14bf11e762e9a863530',
    question:
      'What is the formula to calculate the number of moles from mass and molar mass?',
    correctAnswer: 'Number of moles = Mass / Molar mass',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Number of moles = Mass × Molar mass',
      },
      {
        option: 'Number of moles = Molar mass / Mass',
      },
      {
        option: 'Number of moles = Mass / Molar mass',
      },
      {
        option: 'Number of moles = Mass + Molar mass',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b143f11e762e9a86352d',
    question: 'What is an excess reactant in a chemical reaction?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The reactant that remains after the reaction has gone to completion',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The reactant that is completely consumed first',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The reactant that remains after the reaction has gone to completion',
      },
      {
        option: 'The reactant with the lowest molar mass',
      },
      {
        option: 'The reactant with the highest molar mass',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b132f11e762e9a86352a',
    question:
      'In the reaction N₂ + 3H₂ → 2NH₃, what is the mole ratio of hydrogen to ammonia?',
    correctAnswer: '3:2',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1:1',
      },
      {
        option: '3:2',
      },
      {
        option: '2:3',
      },
      {
        option: '1:2',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b128f11e762e9a863527',
    question:
      'What is the molar volume of a gas at standard temperature and pressure (STP)?',
    correctAnswer: '22.4 L',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '24.5 L',
      },
      {
        option: '22.4 L',
      },
      {
        option: '20.1 L',
      },
      {
        option: '18.2 L',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b11ff11e762e9a863524',
    question: 'How many grams are in 3 moles of CO₂ (molar mass = 44 g/mol)?',
    correctAnswer: '132 grams',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '88 grams',
      },
      {
        option: '132 grams',
      },
      {
        option: '176 grams',
      },
      {
        option: '44 grams',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b118f11e762e9a863521',
    question:
      'In the reaction 4Fe + 3O₂ → 2Fe₂O₃, how many moles of Fe₂O₃ are produced from 6 moles of Fe?',
    correctAnswer: '3 moles',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b10cf11e762e9a86351e',
    question: 'What is percent yield?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The ratio of the actual yield to the theoretical yield, multiplied by 100',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'The ratio of the theoretical yield to the actual yield, multiplied by 100',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The ratio of the actual yield to the theoretical yield, multiplied by 100',
      },
      {
        option: 'The total amount of product formed in a reaction',
      },
      {
        option: 'The amount of reactant left over after a reaction',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b104f11e762e9a86351b',
    question: 'What is the theoretical yield of a reaction?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The maximum amount of product that can be produced from a given amount of reactant',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The actual amount of product obtained from a reaction',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The maximum amount of product that can be produced from a given amount of reactant',
      },
      {
        option: 'The amount of reactant used in a reaction',
      },
      {
        option: 'The amount of product lost during a reaction',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b0f8f11e762e9a863518',
    question: 'What is the limiting reactant in a chemical reaction?',
    correctAnswer: 'The reactant that is completely consumed first',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The reactant that is left over after the reaction',
      },
      {
        option: 'The reactant that is completely consumed first',
      },
      {
        option: 'The reactant that has the highest molar mass',
      },
      {
        option: 'The reactant that has the lowest molar mass',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b0e7f11e762e9a863515',
    question:
      'In the balanced chemical equation 2H₂ + O₂ → 2H₂O, what is the mole ratio of hydrogen to oxygen?',
    correctAnswer: '2:1',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1:1',
      },
      {
        option: '2:1',
      },
      {
        option: '1:2',
      },
      {
        option: '2:2',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b0dcf11e762e9a863512',
    question: 'What is the molar mass of water (H₂O)?',
    correctAnswer: '18 g/mol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '16 g/mol',
      },
      {
        option: '18 g/mol',
      },
      {
        option: '20 g/mol',
      },
      {
        option: '22 g/mol',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b0d1f11e762e9a86350f',
    question: "What does the term 'mole ratio' refer to in stoichiometry?",
    correctAnswer:
      'The ratio of moles of one substance to the moles of another substance in a balanced equation',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'The ratio of the mass of one substance to the mass of another substance',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The ratio of moles of one substance to the moles of another substance in a balanced equation',
      },
      {
        option: 'The ratio of the volume of gases involved in a reaction',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The ratio of the energy produced to the energy consumed in a reaction',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676b091f11e762e9a86350c',
    question: 'What is stoichiometry?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The calculation of reactants and products in chemical reactions',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    chapter: 'Stoichiometry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The study of chemical bonding',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The calculation of reactants and products in chemical reactions',
      },
      {
        option: 'The analysis of chemical properties',
      },
      {
        option: 'The study of atomic structure',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bef805f31fc07fe5029',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule is a polysaccharide found in the exoskeletons of insects and crustaceans?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chitin',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Starch',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cellulose',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glycogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chitin',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764be7805f31fc07fe5026',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule is a polymer of glucose molecules and is stored in animal liver and muscle cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Glycogen',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Starch',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cellulose',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glycogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chitin',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bdf805f31fc07fe5023',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule provides structural support to plants and is the most abundant organic compound on Earth?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cellulose',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Starch',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cellulose',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glycogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chitin',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bd7805f31fc07fe5020',
    question: 'Which category of biological molecules includes DNA and RNA?',
    correctAnswer: 'Nucleic acids',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bcf805f31fc07fe501d',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule is essential for long-term energy storage and insulation?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lipids',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bc8805f31fc07fe501a',
    question:
      'Which category of biological molecules includes cellulose and starch?',
    correctAnswer: 'Carbohydrates',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bc0805f31fc07fe5017',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule is hydrophobic and includes fats, oils, and waxes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lipids',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bb7805f31fc07fe5014',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule has a structure consisting of a phosphate group, a sugar, and a nitrogenous base?',
    correctAnswer: 'Nucleic acids',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764bb0805f31fc07fe5011',
    question: 'Which biological molecule is composed of amino acids?',
    correctAnswer: 'Proteins',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764ba3805f31fc07fe500e',
    question: 'What is the primary function of proteins in living organisms?',
    correctAnswer: 'Enzymes and structural components',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Energy storage',
      },
      {
        option: 'Genetic information storage',
      },
      {
        option: 'Enzymes and structural components',
      },
      {
        option: 'Quick energy source',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b9b805f31fc07fe500b',
    question:
      'Which category of biological molecules includes steroids and hormones?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lipids',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b95805f31fc07fe5008',
    question: 'Which biological molecule stores genetic information?',
    correctAnswer: 'Nucleic acids',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b8d805f31fc07fe5005',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule is the primary source of quick energy in cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Carbohydrates',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b85805f31fc07fe5002',
    question: 'Which category of biological molecules includes enzymes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Proteins',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b73805f31fc07fe4ffe',
    question:
      'Which biological molecule is the main component of cell membranes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lipids',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Biological Molecules',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbohydrates',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lipids',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleic acids',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b3f805f31fc07fe4ffb',
    question: 'What is the function of the cell wall in plant cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Provides structural support and protection.',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Regulates the passage of substances into and out of the cell.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Stores water and nutrients.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Produces energy.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Provides structural support and protection.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b38805f31fc07fe4ff8',
    question:
      'Which cellular structure is responsible for coordinating cell division in animal cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Centriole',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ribosome',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centriole',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloroplast',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b30805f31fc07fe4ff5',
    question:
      'Which organelle is responsible for the synthesis of lipids and steroids?',
    correctAnswer: 'Smooth endoplasmic reticulum',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Rough endoplasmic reticulum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Golgi apparatus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Smooth endoplasmic reticulum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lysosome',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b27805f31fc07fe4ff2',
    question: 'Which statement best describes the function of the nucleus?',
    correctAnswer:
      'It contains the genetic material and controls cellular activities.',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It synthesizes proteins.',
      },
      {
        option: 'It generates energy for the cell.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'It regulates the passage of substances into and out of the cell.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'It contains the genetic material and controls cellular activities.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b1e805f31fc07fe4fef',
    question:
      'Which organelle contains chlorophyll and is responsible for photosynthesis in plant cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chloroplast',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Mitochondria',
      },
      {
        option: 'Golgi apparatus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloroplast',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lysosome',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b16805f31fc07fe4fec',
    question: 'What is the function of the central vacuole in plant cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Stores water and maintains turgor pressure.',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Breaks down cellular waste.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Synthesizes proteins.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Stores water and maintains turgor pressure.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Modifies and packages proteins.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b0e805f31fc07fe4fe9',
    question:
      'Which cellular structure is responsible for maintaining cell shape and providing structural support?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cytoskeleton',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Cell membrane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cytoplasm',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cytoskeleton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centriole',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764b06805f31fc07fe4fe6',
    question:
      'Which organelle contains digestive enzymes to break down cellular waste?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lysosome',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Nucleus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Golgi apparatus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lysosome',
      },
      {
        option: 'Endoplasmic reticulum',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764afe805f31fc07fe4fe3',
    question: 'What is the function of the cell membrane?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Regulates the passage of substances into and out of the cell.',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Stores genetic material.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Produces energy.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Regulates the passage of substances into and out of the cell.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Synthesizes proteins.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764af6805f31fc07fe4fe0',
    question:
      'Which structure is found in plant cells but not in animal cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chloroplast',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Mitochondria',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lysosome',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloroplast',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centriole',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764aee805f31fc07fe4fdd',
    question:
      'Which organelle is involved in the modification, packaging, and secretion of proteins?',
    correctAnswer: 'Golgi apparatus',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Endoplasmic reticulum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lysosome',
      },
      {
        option: 'Golgi apparatus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ribosome',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764ae7805f31fc07fe4fda',
    question:
      'Which organelle is responsible for detoxifying harmful substances in the cell?',
    correctAnswer: 'Smooth endoplasmic reticulum',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Golgi apparatus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Smooth endoplasmic reticulum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lysosome',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vacuole',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764ad5805f31fc07fe4fd7',
    question: 'What is the function of ribosomes in a cell?',
    correctAnswer: 'Protein synthesis',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Energy production',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lipid synthesis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Protein synthesis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Waste disposal',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764acd805f31fc07fe4fd4',
    question:
      'Which cellular structure contains the genetic material of the cell?',
    correctAnswer: 'Nucleus',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Mitochondria',
      },
      {
        option: 'Endoplasmic reticulum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lysosome',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764aba805f31fc07fe4fd0',
    question: 'Which organelle is known as the powerhouse of the cell?',
    correctAnswer: 'Mitochondria',
    class: 'Biology',
    chapter: 'Cell Structure And Function',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Nucleus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Endoplasmic reticulum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mitochondria',
      },
      {
        option: 'Golgi apparatus',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a72805f31fc07fe4fcd',
    question:
      'What is the term for the process where a gas changes directly to a solid?',
    correctAnswer: 'Deposition',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Sublimation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Condensation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Evaporation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Deposition',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a6a805f31fc07fe4fca',
    question:
      'Which law of thermodynamics states that energy cannot be created or destroyed?',
    correctAnswer: 'First law',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Zeroth law',
      },
      {
        option: 'First law',
      },
      {
        option: 'Second law',
      },
      {
        option: 'Third law',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a61805f31fc07fe4fc7',
    question: 'What happens to the entropy of an isolated system over time?',
    correctAnswer: 'It increases.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It decreases.',
      },
      {
        option: 'It remains constant.',
      },
      {
        option: 'It fluctuates.',
      },
      {
        option: 'It increases.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a5a805f31fc07fe4fc4',
    question: 'What is specific heat capacity?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The amount of heat required to raise the temperature of one kilogram of a substance by one degree Celsius.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'The amount of heat required to change the phase of a substance.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The amount of heat required to melt a substance.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The amount of heat required to raise the temperature of one kilogram of a substance by one degree Celsius.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The amount of heat required to boil a substance.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a53805f31fc07fe4fc1',
    question:
      'Which law of thermodynamics states that heat always flows from a hot body to a cold body?',
    correctAnswer: 'Second law',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Zeroth law',
      },
      {
        option: 'First law',
      },
      {
        option: 'Second law',
      },
      {
        option: 'Third law',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a4b805f31fc07fe4fbe',
    question: 'What is entropy?',
    correctAnswer: 'A measure of the disorder or randomness in a system.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A measure of the internal energy of a system.',
      },
      {
        option: 'A measure of the pressure in a system.',
      },
      {
        option: 'A measure of the disorder or randomness in a system.',
      },
      {
        option: 'A measure of the temperature of a system.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a43805f31fc07fe4fbb',
    question:
      'What is the term for the maximum efficiency of a heat engine operating between two temperatures?',
    correctAnswer: 'Carnot efficiency',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Efficiency ratio',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carnot efficiency',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thermal efficiency',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ideal efficiency',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a3c805f31fc07fe4fb8',
    question:
      "What is the relationship between pressure, volume, and temperature in Boyle's law?",
    correctAnswer: 'Pressure × Volume = Constant',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Pressure × Volume = Constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pressure × Temperature = Constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'Volume × Temperature = Constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pressure ÷ Volume = Constant',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a34805f31fc07fe4fb5',
    question: "What does the term 'adiabatic' mean in thermodynamics?",
    correctAnswer: 'No heat exchange with the surroundings.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Constant pressure',
      },
      {
        option: 'Constant temperature',
      },
      {
        option: 'No work done by the system',
      },
      {
        option: 'No heat exchange with the surroundings.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a2c805f31fc07fe4fb2',
    question: 'Which process occurs when a gas expands freely into a vacuum?',
    correctAnswer: 'Isothermal',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Adiabatic',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isothermal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isobaric',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isochoric',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a24805f31fc07fe4faf',
    question: 'What is the unit of heat energy in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Joule',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Calorie',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a13805f31fc07fe4fac',
    question: 'What is the second law of thermodynamics?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The entropy of an isolated system always increases over time.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'Energy cannot be created or destroyed, only converted from one form to another.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Heat always flows from a hot body to a cold body.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The entropy of an isolated system always increases over time.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The internal energy of a system remains constant if no energy is added or removed.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764a0b805f31fc07fe4fa9',
    question: 'Which quantity remains constant during an adiabatic process?',
    correctAnswer: 'Entropy',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Pressure',
      },
      {
        option: 'Volume',
      },
      {
        option: 'Temperature',
      },
      {
        option: 'Entropy',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667649f4805f31fc07fe4fa5',
    question: 'What is the first law of thermodynamics?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Energy cannot be created or destroyed, only converted from one form to another.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Thermodynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Heat always flows from a hot body to a cold body.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Energy cannot be created or destroyed, only converted from one form to another.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The entropy of an isolated system always increases.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The internal energy of a system remains constant if no energy is added or removed.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764988805f31fc07fe4fa2',
    question:
      'What is the purpose of using a diffraction grating in optical experiments?',
    correctAnswer: 'To disperse light into its component wavelengths.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Physical Optics Notes',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To reflect light off a surface.',
      },
      {
        option: 'To disperse light into its component wavelengths.',
      },
      {
        option: 'To absorb light at specific wavelengths.',
      },
      {
        option: 'To polarize light waves.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764980805f31fc07fe4f9f',
    question: 'Which phenomenon demonstrates the wave nature of light?',
    correctAnswer: 'Interference',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Physical Optics Notes',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Reflection',
      },
      {
        option: 'Interference',
      },
      {
        option: 'Refraction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Absorption',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676496c805f31fc07fe4f9c',
    question: "What does Huygens' principle state about wavefronts?",
    correctAnswer:
      'Every point on a wavefront acts as a source of secondary wavelets.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Physical Optics Notes',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'Every point on a wavefront acts as a source of secondary wavelets.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Every point on a wavefront reflects light waves.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Every point on a wavefront refracts light waves.',
      },
      {
        option: 'Every point on a wavefront diffracts light waves.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764960805f31fc07fe4f99',
    question: 'What is the condition for constructive interference?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The path difference between the two waves is an integer multiple of the wavelength.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Physical Optics Notes',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'The path difference between the two waves is an integer multiple of half the wavelength.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The path difference between the two waves is an integer multiple of the wavelength.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The path difference between the two waves is a non-integer multiple of the wavelength.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The path difference between the two waves is zero.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676493d805f31fc07fe4f95',
    question: "What does the term 'diffraction' refer to in physical optics?",
    correctAnswer:
      'The bending of waves around the edges of an obstacle or aperture.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Physical Optics Notes',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The interference of light waves.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The bending of waves around the edges of an obstacle or aperture.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The reflection of light waves.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The refraction of light waves.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764934805f31fc07fe4f92',
    question: 'What is interference in the context of wave optics?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The phenomenon where two or more waves superpose to form a resultant wave.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Physical Optics Notes',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The bending of waves around obstacles.',
      },
      {
        option: 'The spreading of waves through a narrow aperture.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The phenomenon where two or more waves superpose to form a resultant wave.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The change in direction of waves when they pass from one medium to another.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764919805f31fc07fe4f8e',
    question: 'What is the principle of superposition in wave optics?',
    correctAnswer:
      'When two or more waves overlap, the resultant displacement is the sum of the individual displacements.',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Physical Optics Notes',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'When two or more waves overlap, the resultant displacement is the difference of the individual displacements.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'When two or more waves overlap, the resultant displacement is the sum of the individual displacements.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'When two or more waves overlap, the resultant displacement is the product of the individual displacements.',
      },
      {
        option:
          'When two or more waves overlap, the waves cancel each other out.',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667648d7805f31fc07fe4f8b',
    question:
      'What happens to the speed of a wave as it moves from a less dense to a more dense medium?',
    correctAnswer: 'It decreases',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It increases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It decreases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It remains the same',
      },
      {
        option: 'It oscillates',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667648cf805f31fc07fe4f88',
    question: 'Which of the following best describes a standing wave?',
    correctAnswer: 'A wave that remains in a constant position',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A wave that travels in a straight line',
      },
      {
        option: 'A wave that remains in a constant position',
      },
      {
        option: 'A wave that changes speed and direction',
      },
      {
        option: 'A wave that is absorbed by the medium',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667648c6805f31fc07fe4f85',
    question:
      'What is the term for the change in direction of a wave as it passes from one medium to another?',
    correctAnswer: 'Refraction',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Reflection',
      },
      {
        option: 'Refraction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diffraction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Interference',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667648be805f31fc07fe4f82',
    question:
      'What is the term for the phenomenon where a wave bends around the edges of an obstacle?',
    correctAnswer: 'Diffraction',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Reflection',
      },
      {
        option: 'Refraction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diffraction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Interference',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667648b7805f31fc07fe4f7f',
    question:
      'Which of the following best describes constructive interference?',
    correctAnswer: 'When two waves meet and their amplitudes add up',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'When two waves meet and their amplitudes cancel out',
      },
      {
        option: 'When two waves meet and their frequencies add up',
      },
      {
        option: 'When two waves meet and their amplitudes add up',
      },
      {
        option: 'When two waves meet and their wavelengths become shorter',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667648ae805f31fc07fe4f7c',
    question: 'What is a transverse wave?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A wave where the particles of the medium move perpendicular to the direction of the wave',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'A wave where the particles of the medium move parallel to the direction of the wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'A wave that requires a medium to propagate',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A wave where the particles of the medium move perpendicular to the direction of the wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'A wave that does not require a medium to propagate',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667648a7805f31fc07fe4f79',
    question:
      "What does the term 'frequency' refer to in the context of waves?",
    correctAnswer: 'The number of waves passing a point per unit time',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The distance between two consecutive crests',
      },
      {
        option: 'The time taken for one complete cycle',
      },
      {
        option: 'The maximum displacement from the equilibrium position',
      },
      {
        option: 'The number of waves passing a point per unit time',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676489f805f31fc07fe4f76',
    question: 'What type of wave is light?',
    correctAnswer: 'Electromagnetic wave',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Transverse wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Longitudinal wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electromagnetic wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Surface wave',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764896805f31fc07fe4f73',
    question: 'What is the period of a wave?',
    correctAnswer: 'The time taken for one complete cycle',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The distance between two consecutive crests',
      },
      {
        option: 'The time taken for one complete cycle',
      },
      {
        option: 'The maximum displacement from the equilibrium position',
      },
      {
        option: 'The number of waves passing a point per unit time',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676488d805f31fc07fe4f70',
    question: 'Which type of wave requires a medium to propagate?',
    correctAnswer: 'Mechanical wave',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Electromagnetic wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mechanical wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transverse wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Surface wave',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764885805f31fc07fe4f6d',
    question: 'What is the amplitude of a wave?',
    correctAnswer: 'The maximum displacement from the equilibrium position',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The distance between two crests',
      },
      {
        option: 'The time taken for one complete cycle',
      },
      {
        option: 'The maximum displacement from the equilibrium position',
      },
      {
        option: 'The number of waves passing a point per unit time',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676487b805f31fc07fe4f6a',
    question: 'What is the formula for wave speed?',
    correctAnswer: 'Wave speed = Frequency × Wavelength',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Wave speed = Frequency / Wavelength',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wave speed = Frequency × Wavelength',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wave speed = Wavelength / Period',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wave speed = Amplitude × Frequency',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764873805f31fc07fe4f67',
    question: 'What type of wave is sound?',
    correctAnswer: 'Longitudinal wave',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Transverse wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Longitudinal wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electromagnetic wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Surface wave',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764860805f31fc07fe4f63',
    question:
      'What is the term for the distance between two consecutive crests of a wave?',
    correctAnswer: 'Wavelength',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Waves',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Frequency',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amplitude',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wavelength',
      },
      {
        option: 'Period',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764820805f31fc07fe4f5f',
    question: 'What is the natural frequency of an oscillating system?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The frequency at which the system oscillates when not subjected to a continuous or repeated external force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'The frequency at which the system oscillates when subjected to a continuous external force',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The frequency at which the system oscillates when not subjected to a continuous or repeated external force',
      },
      {
        option: 'The frequency at which the amplitude of oscillation is zero',
      },
      {
        option: "The frequency at which the system's kinetic energy is maximum",
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764819805f31fc07fe4f5c',
    question:
      'What is the term for the maximum speed of a simple harmonic oscillator?',
    correctAnswer: 'Maximum Velocity',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Maximum Acceleration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maximum Displacement',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maximum Velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maximum Frequency',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764810805f31fc07fe4f59',
    question:
      'Which type of oscillation occurs when the driving force is removed and the system oscillates at its natural frequency?',
    correctAnswer: 'Free Oscillation',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Forced Oscillation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Damped Oscillation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Free Oscillation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Resonant Oscillation',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764808805f31fc07fe4f56',
    question:
      'What is the effect of increasing the mass of a simple pendulum on its period?',
    correctAnswer: 'No effect',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Increases the period',
      },
      {
        option: 'Decreases the period',
      },
      {
        option: 'No effect',
      },
      {
        option: 'Depends on the amplitude',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647fd805f31fc07fe4f53',
    question:
      'What is the relationship between frequency (f) and period (T) of an oscillation?',
    correctAnswer: 'f = 1/T',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'f = T',
      },
      {
        option: 'f = T/2',
      },
      {
        option: 'f = 1/T',
      },
      {
        option: 'f = 2T',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647f6805f31fc07fe4f50',
    question:
      'What happens to the total mechanical energy of a damped harmonic oscillator over time?',
    correctAnswer: 'It decreases',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It remains constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'It increases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It decreases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It fluctuates',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647ee805f31fc07fe4f4d',
    question:
      'Which type of energy is at its maximum when a simple harmonic oscillator is at its maximum displacement?',
    correctAnswer: 'Potential Energy',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Kinetic Energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thermal Energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Potential Energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mechanical Energy',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647e5805f31fc07fe4f4a',
    question:
      'What is the phase difference between two points on a wave separated by a distance equal to one wavelength?',
    correctAnswer: '360 degrees or 2π radians',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '90 degrees or π/2 radians',
      },
      {
        option: '180 degrees or π radians',
      },
      {
        option: '270 degrees or 3π/2 radians',
      },
      {
        option: '360 degrees or 2π radians',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647db805f31fc07fe4f47',
    question: 'Which of the following best describes resonance?',
    correctAnswer:
      'When the frequency of external force matches the natural frequency of the system',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'When the amplitude of oscillation is zero',
      },
      {
        option:
          'When the frequency of external force is higher than the natural frequency',
      },
      {
        option:
          'When the frequency of external force matches the natural frequency of the system',
      },
      {
        option: 'When the damping force is maximum',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647d2805f31fc07fe4f44',
    question: "What does the term 'damping' refer to in oscillations?",
    correctAnswer: 'The gradual loss of amplitude over time',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The increase in frequency over time',
      },
      {
        option: 'The gradual loss of amplitude over time',
      },
      {
        option: 'The sudden stop of oscillations',
      },
      {
        option: 'The phase shift in oscillations',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647cb805f31fc07fe4f41',
    question: 'What is the formula for the period of a simple pendulum?',
    correctAnswer: 'T = 2π√(L/g)',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'T = 2π√(g/L)',
      },
      {
        option: 'T = 2π(L/g)',
      },
      {
        option: 'T = 2π√(L/g)',
      },
      {
        option: 'T = 2π√(L*g)',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647c3805f31fc07fe4f3e',
    question:
      'Which type of oscillation occurs when the restoring force is directly proportional to the displacement?',
    correctAnswer: 'Simple Harmonic Motion',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Damped Oscillation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Forced Oscillation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Simple Harmonic Motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'Resonant Oscillation',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647bb805f31fc07fe4f3b',
    question: 'What does the amplitude of an oscillation represent?',
    correctAnswer: 'The maximum displacement from the equilibrium position',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The time taken for one complete cycle',
      },
      {
        option: 'The maximum displacement from the equilibrium position',
      },
      {
        option: 'The rate of oscillation',
      },
      {
        option: 'The phase difference between two points',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667647b3805f31fc07fe4f38',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of frequency?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hertz',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hertz',
      },
      {
        option: 'Meter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676479f805f31fc07fe4f34',
    question:
      'What is the term for the time taken for one complete cycle of oscillation?',
    correctAnswer: 'Period',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Oscillation',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Frequency',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amplitude',
      },
      {
        option: 'Period',
      },
      {
        option: 'Phase',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764763805f31fc07fe4f31',
    question:
      'Which equation describes the relationship between pressure, velocity, and height in a flowing fluid?',
    correctAnswer: "Bernoulli's equation",
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Bernoulli's equation",
      },
      {
        option: 'Continuity equation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Navier-Stokes equation',
      },
      {
        option: "Euler's equation",
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676475c805f31fc07fe4f2e',
    question: "What does the term 'streamline' refer to in fluid flow?",
    correctAnswer:
      'A line that is tangent to the velocity of the fluid at any point',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A line that represents the pressure gradient',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A line that is tangent to the velocity of the fluid at any point',
      },
      {
        option: 'A line that represents the temperature gradient',
      },
      {
        option: 'A line that shows the density variation in the fluid',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764754805f31fc07fe4f2b',
    question:
      'Which principle is used to explain the lift force on an airplane wing?',
    correctAnswer: "Bernoulli's principle",
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Archimedes' principle",
      },
      {
        option: "Pascal's principle",
      },
      {
        option: "Bernoulli's principle",
      },
      {
        option: 'Continuity principle',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676474c805f31fc07fe4f28',
    question: 'What is the main assumption of ideal fluid flow?',
    correctAnswer: 'The fluid is incompressible and has no viscosity',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The fluid is compressible and has viscosity',
      },
      {
        option: 'The fluid is incompressible and has viscosity',
      },
      {
        option: 'The fluid is incompressible and has no viscosity',
      },
      {
        option: 'The fluid is compressible and has no viscosity',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764745805f31fc07fe4f25',
    question: 'What is the term for the study of fluids at rest?',
    correctAnswer: 'Fluid statics',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Fluid dynamics',
      },
      {
        option: 'Fluid statics',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hydraulics',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hydrodynamics',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676473d805f31fc07fe4f22',
    question:
      'Which force acts on a body moving through a fluid and opposes its motion?',
    correctAnswer: 'Drag force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lift force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Buoyant force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Drag force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centripetal force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764736805f31fc07fe4f1f',
    question:
      'In the continuity equation, what remains constant for an incompressible fluid?',
    correctAnswer: 'Mass flow rate',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Pressure',
      },
      {
        option: 'Velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mass flow rate',
      },
      {
        option: 'Temperature',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764729805f31fc07fe4f1c',
    question: "Which equation represents Bernoulli's principle?",
    correctAnswer: 'P + 0.5ρv² + ρgh = constant',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'P + 0.5ρv² + ρgh = constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'P = ρgh',
      },
      {
        option: 'P + ρv = constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'P = 0.5ρv²',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764722805f31fc07fe4f19',
    question: "What does the term 'viscosity' refer to in fluid dynamics?",
    correctAnswer: "A measure of a fluid's resistance to deformation",
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "A measure of a fluid's density",
      },
      {
        option: "A measure of a fluid's resistance to deformation",
      },
      {
        option: "A measure of a fluid's temperature",
      },
      {
        option: "A measure of a fluid's pressure",
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676471b805f31fc07fe4f16',
    question: 'What is the Reynolds number used to predict?',
    correctAnswer: 'The type of flow in a fluid system',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The pressure in a fluid system',
      },
      {
        option: 'The velocity in a fluid system',
      },
      {
        option: 'The type of flow in a fluid system',
      },
      {
        option: 'The temperature in a fluid system',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764714805f31fc07fe4f13',
    question:
      'Which type of flow is characterized by smooth and orderly fluid motion?',
    correctAnswer: 'Laminar flow',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Turbulent flow',
      },
      {
        option: 'Laminar flow',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chaotic flow',
      },
      {
        option: 'Circular flow',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676470c805f31fc07fe4f10',
    question: 'What is the unit of dynamic viscosity in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Pascal-second',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Newton-second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pascal-second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joule-second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt-second',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764705805f31fc07fe4f0d',
    question:
      "What does Bernoulli's principle state about the relationship between velocity and pressure in a moving fluid?",
    correctAnswer:
      'As the velocity of a fluid increases, its pressure decreases',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'As the velocity of a fluid increases, its pressure increases',
      },
      {
        option: 'As the velocity of a fluid increases, its pressure decreases',
      },
      {
        option: 'Velocity and pressure in a fluid are independent',
      },
      {
        option: 'As the pressure of a fluid increases, its velocity decreases',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667646fd805f31fc07fe4f0a',
    question:
      'Which equation is used to describe the conservation of mass in fluid dynamics?',
    correctAnswer: 'Continuity equation',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Bernoulli's equation",
      },
      {
        option: 'Navier-Stokes equation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Continuity equation',
      },
      {
        option: "Euler's equation",
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667646d6805f31fc07fe4f06',
    question: 'What is the study of fluid dynamics concerned with?',
    correctAnswer: 'The behavior of fluids in motion',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Fluid Dynamics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The study of fluids at rest',
      },
      {
        option: 'The behavior of fluids in motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'The study of solid objects in motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'The study of gases in a vacuum',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764694805f31fc07fe4f03',
    question: 'What is the direction of angular velocity in rotational motion?',
    correctAnswer: 'Perpendicular to the plane of rotation',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Along the radius of the circle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Parallel to the plane of rotation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Perpendicular to the plane of rotation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tangential to the circle',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676468b805f31fc07fe4f00',
    question: "What does the term 'centrifugal force' describe?",
    correctAnswer:
      'A fictitious force that appears to act outward on a mass when it is in a rotating frame of reference',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'A real force that pulls objects inward towards the center of rotation',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A fictitious force that appears to act outward on a mass when it is in a rotating frame of reference',
      },
      {
        option: 'A force that acts parallel to the direction of motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'A force that is equal to the weight of the object',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764681805f31fc07fe4efd',
    question:
      "In rotational motion, what does the term 'moment of inertia' depend on?",
    correctAnswer: 'The mass distribution relative to the axis of rotation',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The velocity of the object',
      },
      {
        option: 'The force applied to the object',
      },
      {
        option: 'The mass distribution relative to the axis of rotation',
      },
      {
        option: 'The angular acceleration of the object',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676467a805f31fc07fe4efa',
    question: 'What is the formula for angular momentum (L)?',
    correctAnswer: 'L = I * ω',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'L = m * v * r',
      },
      {
        option: 'L = I * ω',
      },
      {
        option: 'L = F * r',
      },
      {
        option: 'L = m * a * r',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764672805f31fc07fe4ef7',
    question: 'What is the unit of torque in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Newton-meter',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton-meter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676466b805f31fc07fe4ef4',
    question: "What does the term 'angular acceleration' refer to?",
    correctAnswer: 'The rate of change of angular velocity',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The rate of change of linear velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'The rate of change of angular displacement',
      },
      {
        option: 'The rate of change of angular velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'The rate of change of torque',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764663805f31fc07fe4ef1',
    question:
      'Which force is responsible for keeping an object moving in a circular path?',
    correctAnswer: 'Centripetal force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Gravitational force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Frictional force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centripetal force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centrifugal force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676465c805f31fc07fe4eee',
    question:
      'What is the relationship between linear velocity (v) and angular velocity (ω) in circular motion?',
    correctAnswer: 'v = r * ω',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'v = ω / r',
      },
      {
        option: 'v = r * ω',
      },
      {
        option: 'v = r² * ω',
      },
      {
        option: 'v = ω² / r',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764654805f31fc07fe4eeb',
    question: 'Which quantity measures the rotational inertia of an object?',
    correctAnswer: 'Moment of inertia',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Torque',
      },
      {
        option: 'Angular momentum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Moment of inertia',
      },
      {
        option: 'Angular velocity',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676464c805f31fc07fe4ee8',
    question:
      'In circular motion, what is the direction of the centripetal acceleration?',
    correctAnswer: 'Towards the center of the circle',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Away from the center of the circle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tangential to the circle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Towards the center of the circle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Parallel to the velocity vector',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764644805f31fc07fe4ee5',
    question: 'What is the formula for calculating torque?',
    correctAnswer: 'Torque = Force × Lever Arm Distance',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Torque = Force / Lever Arm Distance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Torque = Force × Lever Arm Distance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Torque = Mass × Acceleration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Torque = Mass × Velocity',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676463c805f31fc07fe4ee2',
    question: "What does the term 'torque' refer to?",
    correctAnswer: 'A measure of the force that can cause an object to rotate',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The rate of change of velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'The force that resists motion between two surfaces',
      },
      {
        option: 'A measure of the force that can cause an object to rotate',
      },
      {
        option: 'The distance an object travels per unit time',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764633805f31fc07fe4edf',
    question: 'Which of the following best describes angular displacement?',
    correctAnswer: 'The angle through which an object moves on a circular path',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The distance traveled along a circular path',
      },
      {
        option: 'The rate of change of angular velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'The angle through which an object moves on a circular path',
      },
      {
        option: 'The force required to keep an object moving in a circle',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676462b805f31fc07fe4edc',
    question: 'What is the formula for centripetal force?',
    correctAnswer: 'F = m*v²/r',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'F = m*a',
      },
      {
        option: 'F = m*v²/r',
      },
      {
        option: 'F = m*g',
      },
      {
        option: 'F = m*r²/v',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66764614805f31fc07fe4ed8',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of angular velocity?',
    correctAnswer: 'Radians per second',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Rotational & Circular Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Meters per second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Degrees per second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Radians per second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Revolutions per minute',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644c24cea5d5913fade77',
    question:
      'Which type of energy transformation occurs in a hydroelectric power plant?',
    correctAnswer: 'Gravitational potential energy to electrical energy',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Chemical energy to thermal energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Kinetic energy to thermal energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gravitational potential energy to electrical energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thermal energy to kinetic energy',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644ba4cea5d5913fade74',
    question:
      'What happens to the kinetic energy of an object if its velocity is doubled?',
    correctAnswer: 'It quadruples',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It remains the same',
      },
      {
        option: 'It doubles',
      },
      {
        option: 'It triples',
      },
      {
        option: 'It quadruples',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644b34cea5d5913fade71',
    question: 'Which of the following is an example of mechanical energy?',
    correctAnswer: 'A moving car',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A moving car',
      },
      {
        option: 'Heat from a fire',
      },
      {
        option: 'Light from a bulb',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sound from a speaker',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644ab4cea5d5913fade6e',
    question:
      'What type of energy is stored in a stretched or compressed spring?',
    correctAnswer: 'Elastic Potential Energy',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Kinetic Energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gravitational Potential Energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Elastic Potential Energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thermal Energy',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644a34cea5d5913fade6b',
    question: 'What is the formula for calculating power?',
    correctAnswer: 'Power = Work / Time',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Power = Work × Time',
      },
      {
        option: 'Power = Work / Time',
      },
      {
        option: 'Power = Force × Distance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Power = Mass × Acceleration',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644994cea5d5913fade68',
    question: 'How is power defined in physics?',
    correctAnswer: 'The rate at which work is done',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The rate at which work is done',
      },
      {
        option: 'The amount of force applied over a distance',
      },
      {
        option: 'The change in kinetic energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'The energy stored in an object',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644904cea5d5913fade65',
    question: 'What is the unit of power in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Watt',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pascal',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644884cea5d5913fade62',
    question: 'What does the law of conservation of energy state?',
    correctAnswer: 'Energy cannot be created or destroyed, only transformed',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Energy cannot be created or destroyed, only transformed',
      },
      {
        option: 'Energy can be created but not destroyed',
      },
      {
        option: 'Energy can be destroyed but not created',
      },
      {
        option: 'Energy can neither be created nor destroyed',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676447f4cea5d5913fade5f',
    question: 'What is the formula for gravitational potential energy?',
    correctAnswer: 'PE = Mass × Gravitational Acceleration × Height',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'PE = Mass × Velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'PE = Mass × Gravitational Acceleration × Height',
      },
      {
        option: 'PE = 0.5 × Mass × Velocity²',
      },
      {
        option: 'PE = Force × Distance',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644774cea5d5913fade5c',
    question: 'What is potential energy?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The energy an object possesses due to its position or condition',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The energy an object possesses due to its motion',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The energy an object possesses due to its position or condition',
      },
      {
        option: 'The energy transferred by heat',
      },
      {
        option: 'The energy stored in chemical bonds',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676446e4cea5d5913fade59',
    question: 'What is the formula for calculating kinetic energy?',
    correctAnswer: 'KE = 0.5 × Mass × Velocity²',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'KE = Mass × Velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'KE = 0.5 × Mass × Velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'KE = 0.5 × Mass × Velocity²',
      },
      {
        option: 'KE = Mass × Velocity²',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644664cea5d5913fade56',
    question: 'What is kinetic energy?',
    correctAnswer: 'The energy an object possesses due to its motion',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The energy stored in an object',
      },
      {
        option: 'The energy an object possesses due to its position',
      },
      {
        option: 'The energy an object possesses due to its motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'The energy transferred by heat',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676445e4cea5d5913fade53',
    question:
      'What is the formula for calculating work done by a constant force?',
    correctAnswer: 'Work = Force × Distance × cos(θ)',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Work = Force × Distance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Work = Force × Distance × sin(θ)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Work = Force × Distance × cos(θ)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Work = Mass × Acceleration',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644354cea5d5913fade4d',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of work?',
    correctAnswer: 'Joule',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Work & Energy',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pascal',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667644004cea5d5913fade4a',
    question:
      'Which law describes the relationship between the force acting on an object, its mass, and its acceleration?',
    correctAnswer: "Newton's Second Law of Motion",
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Newton's First Law of Motion",
      },
      {
        option: "Newton's Second Law of Motion",
      },
      {
        option: "Newton's Third Law of Motion",
      },
      {
        option: 'Law of Universal Gravitation',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643f84cea5d5913fade47',
    question: 'Which force acts towards the center in circular motion?',
    correctAnswer: 'Centripetal Force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Centrifugal Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centripetal Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gravitational Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Frictional Force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643f04cea5d5913fade44',
    question:
      'Which type of motion occurs when an object moves in a straight line with constant speed?',
    correctAnswer: 'Uniform Motion',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Uniform Motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'Non-uniform Motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'Circular Motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oscillatory Motion',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643e84cea5d5913fade41',
    question: 'What does the slope of a velocity-time graph represent?',
    correctAnswer: 'Acceleration',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Displacement',
      },
      {
        option: 'Velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acceleration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643de4cea5d5913fade3e',
    question: 'Which force keeps an object moving in a circular path?',
    correctAnswer: 'Centripetal Force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Centrifugal Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Centripetal Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gravitational Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Frictional Force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643d64cea5d5913fade3b',
    question: 'What is the unit of acceleration in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Meters per second squared (m/s²)',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Meters per second (m/s)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Kilometers per hour (km/h)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Meters per second squared (m/s²)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton (N)',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643ce4cea5d5913fade38',
    question: 'What is the effect of a net force acting on an object?',
    correctAnswer: "It causes a change in the object's motion",
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "It increases the object's mass",
      },
      {
        option: "It decreases the object's volume",
      },
      {
        option: "It causes a change in the object's motion",
      },
      {
        option: 'It has no effect on the object',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643c54cea5d5913fade35',
    question:
      'Which force acts against the direction of motion and slows down an object?',
    correctAnswer: 'Frictional Force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Tension Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Applied Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Frictional Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Normal Force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643bd4cea5d5913fade32',
    question:
      'What is the term for the force that pulls objects towards the center of the Earth?',
    correctAnswer: 'Gravitational Force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Magnetic Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electrostatic Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gravitational Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nuclear Force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643b44cea5d5913fade2f',
    question:
      "Which of the following best describes Newton's Third Law of Motion?",
    correctAnswer: 'For every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Force equals mass times acceleration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Objects at rest stay at rest',
      },
      {
        option: 'For every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Energy cannot be created or destroyed',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643ac4cea5d5913fade2c',
    question:
      'What is the term for the resistance to motion when two objects are in contact?',
    correctAnswer: 'Friction',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Inertia',
      },
      {
        option: 'Friction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tension',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gravity',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667643a44cea5d5913fade29',
    question:
      'Which type of force acts perpendicular to the surface of an object in contact with a surface?',
    correctAnswer: 'Normal Force',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Gravitational Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Frictional Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Normal Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tension Force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676439d4cea5d5913fade26',
    question:
      "What is the formula for calculating force according to Newton's Second Law of Motion?",
    correctAnswer: 'Force = Mass × Acceleration',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Force = Mass / Acceleration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Force = Mass × Acceleration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Force = Mass + Acceleration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Force = Mass - Acceleration',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676435d4cea5d5913fade22',
    question:
      'Which law states that an object will remain at rest or in uniform motion unless acted upon by an external force?',
    correctAnswer: "Newton's First Law of Motion",
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Newton's First Law of Motion",
      },
      {
        option: "Newton's Second Law of Motion",
      },
      {
        option: "Newton's Third Law of Motion",
      },
      {
        option: 'Law of Universal Gravitation',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641f94cea5d5913fade1d',
    question: "In vector notation, what does the 'i' component represent?",
    correctAnswer: 'The x-axis component of the vector',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The y-axis component of the vector',
      },
      {
        option: 'The z-axis component of the vector',
      },
      {
        option: 'The x-axis component of the vector',
      },
      {
        option: 'The magnitude of the vector',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641f24cea5d5913fade1a',
    question: 'What is the graphical representation of a vector?',
    correctAnswer: 'An arrow',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A dot',
      },
      {
        option: 'A line',
      },
      {
        option: 'An arrow',
      },
      {
        option: 'A circle',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641ea4cea5d5913fade17',
    question: 'What is the equilibrant of a set of forces?',
    correctAnswer: 'A single force that balances all the other forces',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The resultant of all the forces',
      },
      {
        option: 'A single force that balances all the other forces',
      },
      {
        option: 'A force that is equal to the net force',
      },
      {
        option: 'A force that is perpendicular to the resultant force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641e24cea5d5913fade14',
    question: 'How are the components of a vector typically found?',
    correctAnswer:
      'By projecting the vector onto the axes of a coordinate system',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'By measuring its length',
      },
      {
        option: 'By finding the scalar product',
      },
      {
        option: 'By projecting the vector onto the axes of a coordinate system',
      },
      {
        option: 'By finding the cross product',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641da4cea5d5913fade11',
    question: "What does the term 'equilibrium' refer to in physics?",
    correctAnswer:
      'A state where the sum of forces and torques acting on a body is zero',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'A state where the sum of forces and torques acting on a body is zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'A state of constant motion',
      },
      {
        option: 'A state where all velocities are equal',
      },
      {
        option: 'A state where energy is conserved',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641d34cea5d5913fade0e',
    question:
      'What is the angle between two vectors if their dot product is zero?',
    correctAnswer: '90 degrees',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '0 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '45 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '90 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '180 degrees',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641ca4cea5d5913fade0b',
    question:
      'What is the magnitude of the vector A if its components are Ax = 3 and Ay = 4?',
    correctAnswer: '5',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '3',
      },
      {
        option: '4',
      },
      {
        option: '5',
      },
      {
        option: '7',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641c14cea5d5913fade08',
    question: "What does the term 'resultant vector' refer to?",
    correctAnswer:
      'The single vector which has the same effect as two or more vectors combined',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The vector with the largest magnitude',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The single vector which has the same effect as two or more vectors combined',
      },
      {
        option: 'A vector that is equal and opposite to another vector',
      },
      {
        option: 'A vector that represents the difference between two vectors',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641b84cea5d5913fade05',
    question: 'How is the direction of a vector typically represented?',
    correctAnswer: 'By an angle with respect to a reference axis',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'By a scalar value',
      },
      {
        option: 'By an angle with respect to a reference axis',
      },
      {
        option: 'By its magnitude',
      },
      {
        option: 'By its weight',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641ae4cea5d5913fade02',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a condition for an object to be in static equilibrium?',
    correctAnswer: 'The net torque acting on the object must be zero',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The object must be at rest',
      },
      {
        option: 'The net torque acting on the object must be zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'The object must be moving at a constant velocity',
      },
      {
        option: "The object's acceleration must be zero",
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641a74cea5d5913faddff',
    question: 'In equilibrium, what is the net force acting on an object?',
    correctAnswer: 'Zero',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Equal to its weight',
      },
      {
        option: 'Zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'Equal to the applied force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Equal to the normal force',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676419f4cea5d5913faddfc',
    question:
      'Which operation results in a vector that is perpendicular to two given vectors?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cross product',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Dot product',
      },
      {
        option: 'Scalar product',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cross product',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vector addition',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641974cea5d5913faddf9',
    question: 'What is the dot product of two perpendicular vectors?',
    correctAnswer: 'Zero',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'One',
      },
      {
        option: 'Infinity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Equal to their magnitudes',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641904cea5d5913faddf6',
    question: 'What is the result of vector addition?',
    correctAnswer: 'Resultant vector',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Scalar quantity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Resultant vector',
      },
      {
        option: 'Equilibrium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Component vector',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641884cea5d5913faddf3',
    question: 'Which of the following is a scalar quantity?',
    correctAnswer: 'Temperature',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Velocity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Force',
      },
      {
        option: 'Temperature',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acceleration',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667641494cea5d5913faddef',
    question: 'What is a vector quantity?',
    correctAnswer: 'A quantity that has both magnitude and direction',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A quantity that has only magnitude',
      },
      {
        option: 'A quantity that has both magnitude and direction',
      },
      {
        option: 'A quantity that changes with time',
      },
      {
        option: 'A quantity that has only direction',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640654cea5d5913faddec',
    question: 'What is the unit of pressure in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Pascal',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Pascal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hertz',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640584cea5d5913fadde9',
    question:
      'Which instrument is used to measure small lengths or thicknesses accurately?',
    correctAnswer: 'Micrometer',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Micrometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ruler',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thermometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Barometer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640504cea5d5913fadde6',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of power?',
    correctAnswer: 'Watt',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hertz',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640494cea5d5913fadde3',
    question: 'Which device is used to measure electric resistance?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ohmmeter',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Voltmeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ammeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ohmmeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Galvanometer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640414cea5d5913fadde0',
    question: 'What is the unit of energy in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Joule',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pascal',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676403a4cea5d5913fadddd',
    question: 'Which instrument is used to measure humidity?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hygrometer',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Barometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hygrometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Manometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Anemometer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640324cea5d5913faddda',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of force?',
    correctAnswer: 'Newton',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pascal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640294cea5d5913faddd7',
    question: 'Which device is used to measure voltage?',
    correctAnswer: 'Voltmeter',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ammeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Voltmeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Galvanometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ohmmeter',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640224cea5d5913faddd4',
    question: 'What is the unit of frequency in the SI system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hertz',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hertz',
      },
      {
        option: 'Newton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joule',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pascal',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640194cea5d5913faddd1',
    question: 'Which instrument measures atmospheric pressure?',
    correctAnswer: 'Barometer',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thermometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ammeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Barometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hygrometer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667640144cea5d5913faddce',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of time?',
    correctAnswer: 'Second',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hour',
      },
      {
        option: 'Minute',
      },
      {
        option: 'Second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Day',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676400807a102c43b0c70f9',
    question: 'Which device is used to measure temperature?',
    correctAnswer: 'Thermometer',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Barometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thermometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Voltmeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Manometer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6676400107a102c43b0c70f6',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of electric current?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ampere',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Volt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ampere',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ohm',
      },
      {
        option: 'Watt',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66763ff907a102c43b0c70f3',
    question: 'Which instrument is used to measure mass?',
    correctAnswer: 'Balance',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thermometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Barometer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Balance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Voltmeter',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66763f8407a102c43b0c70ed',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of length?',
    correctAnswer: 'Meter',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Kilogram',
      },
      {
        option: 'Meter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Second',
      },
      {
        option: 'Liter',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec9369866337a65977c1',
    question:
      'Which database model is suitable for representing complex data relationships?',
    correctAnswer: 'Object-oriented',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Relational',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hierarchical',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network',
      },
      {
        option: 'Object-oriented',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec8d69866337a65977be',
    question:
      'What is a stored procedure in the context of database development?',
    correctAnswer: 'A precompiled collection of SQL statements',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A physical backup of a database',
      },
      {
        option: 'A software tool for designing databases',
      },
      {
        option: 'A database schema diagram',
      },
      {
        option: 'A precompiled collection of SQL statements',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec8269866337a65977bb',
    question:
      'Which phase of the software development life cycle (SDLC) includes designing the database schema?',
    correctAnswer: 'Design phase',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Implementation phase',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testing phase',
      },
      {
        option: 'Design phase',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maintenance phase',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec7b69866337a65977b8',
    question:
      'Which database management system (DBMS) is known for its open-source nature and relational database capabilities?',
    correctAnswer: 'MySQL',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Oracle Database',
      },
      {
        option: 'Microsoft SQL Server',
      },
      {
        option: 'MySQL',
      },
      {
        option: 'MongoDB',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec7269866337a65977b5',
    question: 'What is the purpose of indexing in database development?',
    correctAnswer: 'To improve the speed of data retrieval',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store backup copies of data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To enhance data security',
      },
      {
        option: 'To manage user access rights',
      },
      {
        option: 'To improve the speed of data retrieval',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec6b69866337a65977b2',
    question:
      'Which database language is commonly used to manage and manipulate relational databases?',
    correctAnswer: 'SQL',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Java',
      },
      {
        option: 'Python',
      },
      {
        option: 'C#',
      },
      {
        option: 'SQL',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec6369866337a65977af',
    question: 'What does CRUD stand for in database development?',
    correctAnswer: 'Create, Read, Update, Delete',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Compute, Retrieve, Update, Delete',
      },
      {
        option: 'Create, Read, Update, Deploy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Construct, Register, Update, Discard',
      },
      {
        option: 'Create, Read, Update, Delete',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec5b69866337a65977ac',
    question:
      'Which of the following is an advantage of using stored procedures in database development?',
    correctAnswer: 'Improved performance',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Increased data redundancy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Decreased data security',
      },
      {
        option: 'Limited data access',
      },
      {
        option: 'Improved performance',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec5169866337a65977a9',
    question: 'What is the purpose of data modeling in database development?',
    correctAnswer: 'To create a conceptual representation of data structures',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To optimize query performance',
      },
      {
        option: 'To write stored procedures',
      },
      {
        option: 'To secure the database',
      },
      {
        option: 'To create a conceptual representation of data structures',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec4a69866337a65977a6',
    question:
      'Which phase of the database development process involves gathering and analyzing user requirements?',
    correctAnswer: 'Requirements analysis',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Implementation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testing',
      },
      {
        option: 'Requirements analysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maintenance',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec4269866337a65977a3',
    question:
      'Which database model is widely used for organizing data into tables?',
    correctAnswer: 'Relational',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hierarchical',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network',
      },
      {
        option: 'Object-oriented',
      },
      {
        option: 'Relational',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec3969866337a65977a0',
    question:
      'What is the role of a database administrator (DBA) in database development?',
    correctAnswer: 'To manage and maintain the database system',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To design user interfaces',
      },
      {
        option: 'To write SQL queries',
      },
      {
        option: 'To develop database applications',
      },
      {
        option: 'To manage and maintain the database system',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec3169866337a659779d',
    question: 'Which of the following is a key principle of database design?',
    correctAnswer: 'Normalization',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Redundancy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Duplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Normalization',
      },
      {
        option: 'Replication',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ec1a69866337a6597799',
    question: 'What is the purpose of database normalization?',
    correctAnswer: 'To reduce redundancy and improve data integrity',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To increase database size',
      },
      {
        option: 'To speed up query execution',
      },
      {
        option: 'To encrypt sensitive data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To reduce redundancy and improve data integrity',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ebdf69866337a6597795',
    question:
      'Which of the following is not a primary goal of database development?',
    correctAnswer: 'Increasing data redundancy',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database Development',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ensuring data integrity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Improving data security',
      },
      {
        option: 'Optimizing data storage',
      },
      {
        option: 'Increasing data redundancy',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb8a69866337a6597792',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a characteristic of a relational database?',
    correctAnswer: 'Data is organized into tables with rows and columns',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Data is stored in a flat file',
      },
      {
        option: 'Data is organized into tables with rows and columns',
      },
      {
        option: 'Data is encrypted by default',
      },
      {
        option: 'Data is only accessible through a GUI',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb8369866337a659778f',
    question: 'What is a view in a database?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A virtual table based on the result of an SQL SELECT statement',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'A virtual table based on the result of an SQL SELECT statement',
      },
      {
        option: 'A physical copy of a table',
      },
      {
        option: 'A key used to link tables',
      },
      {
        option: 'A set of permissions on a table',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb7969866337a659778c',
    question:
      'Which SQL function is used to return the number of rows in a table?',
    correctAnswer: 'COUNT()',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'SUM()',
      },
      {
        option: 'AVG()',
      },
      {
        option: 'COUNT()',
      },
      {
        option: 'MAX()',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb7169866337a6597789',
    question: 'Which SQL command is used to create a new table in a database?',
    correctAnswer: 'CREATE TABLE',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'CREATE TABLE',
      },
      {
        option: 'INSERT INTO',
      },
      {
        option: 'ALTER TABLE',
      },
      {
        option: 'DROP TABLE',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb6969866337a6597786',
    question: 'What is a database schema?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The structure that defines the organization of data in a database',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A set of queries stored in the database',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The structure that defines the organization of data in a database',
      },
      {
        option: 'The data stored in the database',
      },
      {
        option: 'A backup of the database',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb6169866337a6597783',
    question:
      'Which database object is used to store a collection of related data?',
    correctAnswer: 'Table',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Index',
      },
      {
        option: 'View',
      },
      {
        option: 'Table',
      },
      {
        option: 'Stored Procedure',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb5869866337a6597780',
    question: 'What is the purpose of the JOIN clause in SQL?',
    correctAnswer: 'To combine rows from two or more tables',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To filter query results',
      },
      {
        option: 'To group query results',
      },
      {
        option: 'To sort query results',
      },
      {
        option: 'To combine rows from two or more tables',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb5269866337a659777d',
    question:
      'Which SQL statement is used to modify existing records in a database?',
    correctAnswer: 'UPDATE',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'INSERT',
      },
      {
        option: 'UPDATE',
      },
      {
        option: 'DELETE',
      },
      {
        option: 'SELECT',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb4969866337a659777a',
    question: 'What is a foreign key in a database?',
    correctAnswer: 'A key used to link two tables together',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A unique identifier for each record',
      },
      {
        option: 'A key used to link two tables together',
      },
      {
        option: 'A key used for indexing',
      },
      {
        option: 'A key used for encryption',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb4269866337a6597777',
    question: 'Which SQL clause is used to filter the results of a query?',
    correctAnswer: 'WHERE',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ORDER BY',
      },
      {
        option: 'GROUP BY',
      },
      {
        option: 'HAVING',
      },
      {
        option: 'WHERE',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb3b69866337a6597774',
    question: "What does the term 'normalization' refer to in database design?",
    correctAnswer: 'The process of organizing data to reduce redundancy',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The process of backing up data',
      },
      {
        option: 'The process of organizing data to reduce redundancy',
      },
      {
        option: 'The process of indexing data',
      },
      {
        option: 'The process of encrypting data',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb3369866337a6597771',
    question: 'Which command is used to retrieve data from a database?',
    correctAnswer: 'SELECT',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'INSERT',
      },
      {
        option: 'UPDATE',
      },
      {
        option: 'DELETE',
      },
      {
        option: 'SELECT',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb2c69866337a659776e',
    question: 'What is a primary key in a database?',
    correctAnswer: 'A unique identifier for each record in a table',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A unique identifier for each record in a table',
      },
      {
        option: 'A field that can contain duplicate values',
      },
      {
        option: 'A key that connects two tables',
      },
      {
        option: 'A key used for encrypting data',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eb2569866337a659776b',
    question: 'Which of the following is a type of database model?',
    correctAnswer: 'Relational',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hierarchical',
      },
      {
        option: 'Relational',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network',
      },
      {
        option: 'All of the above',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674eabf69866337a6597767',
    question: 'What does the acronym SQL stand for?',
    correctAnswer: 'Structured Query Language',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Database fundamentals',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Simple Query Language',
      },
      {
        option: 'Structured Query Language',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sequential Query Language',
      },
      {
        option: 'Standard Query Language',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea8969866337a6597764',
    question:
      'Which wireless protocol is designed specifically for personal area networks (PANs)?',
    correctAnswer: 'Bluetooth',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Wi-Fi',
      },
      {
        option: 'Zigbee',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bluetooth',
      },
      {
        option: 'NFC',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea8069866337a6597761',
    question:
      'Which frequency band is commonly used for Bluetooth communication?',
    correctAnswer: '2.4 GHz',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1.8 GHz',
      },
      {
        option: '2.4 GHz',
      },
      {
        option: '5 GHz',
      },
      {
        option: '900 MHz',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea7969866337a659775e',
    question:
      'Which technology is designed for low-power, wide-area networks, often used in IoT devices?',
    correctAnswer: 'LoRaWAN',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Wi-Fi',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bluetooth',
      },
      {
        option: 'LoRaWAN',
      },
      {
        option: 'Zigbee',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea7069866337a659775b',
    question:
      'Which generation of mobile networks is known for enabling high-speed internet and advanced multimedia services?',
    correctAnswer: '4G',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '2G',
      },
      {
        option: '3G',
      },
      {
        option: '4G',
      },
      {
        option: '5G',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea6869866337a6597758',
    question:
      'Which type of wireless network is used to connect devices within a short range, such as in a home or office?',
    correctAnswer: 'WLAN',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'WAN',
      },
      {
        option: 'LAN',
      },
      {
        option: 'WLAN',
      },
      {
        option: 'MAN',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea6069866337a6597755',
    question: 'Which wireless standard is known as WiMAX?',
    correctAnswer: 'IEEE 802.16',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'IEEE 802.11',
      },
      {
        option: 'IEEE 802.15',
      },
      {
        option: 'IEEE 802.16',
      },
      {
        option: 'IEEE 802.3',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea5969866337a6597752',
    question:
      'What is the maximum theoretical data transfer rate of Bluetooth 5.0?',
    correctAnswer: '2 Mbps',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1 Mbps',
      },
      {
        option: '2 Mbps',
      },
      {
        option: '5 Mbps',
      },
      {
        option: '10 Mbps',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea5069866337a659774f',
    question:
      'Which wireless communication technology uses light waves to transmit data?',
    correctAnswer: 'Li-Fi',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Wi-Fi',
      },
      {
        option: 'Li-Fi',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bluetooth',
      },
      {
        option: 'NFC',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea4869866337a659774c',
    question: 'Which protocol is used for secure wireless communication?',
    correctAnswer: 'WPA2',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'WEP',
      },
      {
        option: 'WPA',
      },
      {
        option: 'WPA2',
      },
      {
        option: 'SSL',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea4169866337a6597749',
    question:
      'Which wireless technology is primarily used for mobile phone communication?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cellular',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Wi-Fi',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bluetooth',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cellular',
      },
      {
        option: 'NFC',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea3869866337a6597746',
    question: 'What does the acronym NFC stand for in wireless communication?',
    correctAnswer: 'Near Field Communication',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Near Frequency Communication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Near Field Communication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network Field Communication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network Frequency Communication',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea3169866337a6597743',
    question: 'Which frequency band is commonly used for Wi-Fi networks?',
    correctAnswer: '2.4 GHz and 5 GHz',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '800 MHz and 900 MHz',
      },
      {
        option: '1.8 GHz and 2.1 GHz',
      },
      {
        option: '2.4 GHz and 5 GHz',
      },
      {
        option: '3.6 GHz and 4.9 GHz',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea2969866337a6597740',
    question: 'What does the acronym LTE stand for in wireless communication?',
    correctAnswer: 'Long Term Evolution',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Long Term Evolution',
      },
      {
        option: 'Local Terminal Exchange',
      },
      {
        option: 'Light Transmission Element',
      },
      {
        option: 'Local Transceiver Equipment',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674ea2169866337a659773d',
    question:
      'Which technology is used for short-range wireless communication between devices?',
    correctAnswer: 'Bluetooth',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Wi-Fi',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bluetooth',
      },
      {
        option: 'LTE',
      },
      {
        option: 'NFC',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e9f469866337a6597739',
    question: 'What does the acronym Wi-Fi stand for?',
    correctAnswer: 'Wireless Fidelity',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Wireless communication',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Wide Fidelity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wireless Fiber',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wireless Fidelity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wide Fiber',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e9bf69866337a6597736',
    question:
      'Which protocol is used to access and manage directory information over an IP network?',
    correctAnswer: 'LDAP',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'FTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'LDAP',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e9b769866337a6597733',
    question:
      'Which layer of the OSI model ensures that data is transferred reliably and without errors?',
    correctAnswer: 'Transport Layer',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Network Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transport Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Session Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Data Link Layer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e9af69866337a6597730',
    question:
      'Which protocol is used to assign IP addresses to devices on a network?',
    correctAnswer: 'DHCP',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'DNS',
      },
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'DHCP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e9a769866337a659772d',
    question:
      'Which protocol is used for secure data transmission over the internet?',
    correctAnswer: 'SSL/TLS',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'FTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SSL/TLS',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e9a069866337a659772a',
    question:
      'Which layer of the OSI model provides error detection and correction?',
    correctAnswer: 'Data Link Layer',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Physical Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Data Link Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transport Layer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e99869866337a6597727',
    question:
      'Which protocol is used to transfer files between computers on a network?',
    correctAnswer: 'FTP',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'FTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'IMAP',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e99169866337a6597724',
    question:
      'Which protocol is used for remote login to a server or computer?',
    correctAnswer: 'SSH',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'FTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SSH',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e98969866337a6597721',
    question:
      'Which layer of the OSI model is responsible for routing packets through the network?',
    correctAnswer: 'Network Layer',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Transport Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Session Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Data Link Layer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e98169866337a659771e',
    question: 'What does the IP in IP address stand for?',
    correctAnswer: 'Internet Protocol',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Internet Program',
      },
      {
        option: 'Internet Protocol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Internal Protocol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Interactive Protocol',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e97869866337a659771b',
    question: 'Which protocol is used to retrieve emails from a mail server?',
    correctAnswer: 'IMAP',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'FTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'IMAP',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e97069866337a6597718',
    question: 'Which protocol is used to send emails?',
    correctAnswer: 'SMTP',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'FTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'IMAP',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e96869866337a6597715',
    question:
      'Which layer of the OSI model is responsible for establishing, managing, and terminating connections?',
    correctAnswer: 'Session Layer',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Transport Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Session Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Network Layer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Data Link Layer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e96069866337a6597712',
    question: 'What is the main function of the DNS protocol?',
    correctAnswer: 'To translate domain names to IP addresses',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To transfer files between computers',
      },
      {
        option: 'To send emails',
      },
      {
        option: 'To translate domain names to IP addresses',
      },
      {
        option: 'To establish a connection between devices',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e95869866337a659770f',
    question:
      'Which protocol is used for secure communication over a computer network?',
    correctAnswer: 'HTTPS',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'HTTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'FTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'SMTP',
      },
      {
        option: 'HTTPS',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e93f69866337a659770b',
    question: 'What does the acronym TCP/IP stand for?',
    correctAnswer: 'Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Network communication and protocol',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Transfer Communication Protocol/Internet Protocol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transmission Control Protocol/Internet Protocol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transfer Control Protocol/Internet Protocol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transmission Communication Protocol/Internet Protocol',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e91269866337a6597708',
    question:
      'Which port on the motherboard is used to connect the system to a network?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ethernet port',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'USB port',
      },
      {
        option: 'HDMI port',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethernet port',
      },
      {
        option: 'VGA port',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e90a69866337a6597705',
    question: 'What does GPU stand for, and what is its function?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Graphics Processing Unit; it handles rendering of images and video',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'General Processing Unit; it manages general system operations',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Graphics Processing Unit; it handles rendering of images and video',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gigahertz Processing Unit; it determines the CPU speed',
      },
      {
        option: 'Graphics Performance Unit; it enhances gaming performance',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e90269866337a6597702',
    question:
      'Which component temporarily stores data that the CPU frequently accesses?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cache',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cache',
      },
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8f869866337a65976ff',
    question: 'What is the role of the system clock in a computer?',
    correctAnswer: 'To synchronize the operations of all parts of the computer',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store the date and time',
      },
      {
        option: 'To generate random numbers',
      },
      {
        option: 'To synchronize the operations of all parts of the computer',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide backup power',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8f169866337a65976fc',
    question: 'Which storage device uses flash memory and has no moving parts?',
    correctAnswer: 'Solid State Drive (SSD)',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Solid State Drive (SSD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Optical Drive',
      },
      {
        option: 'Floppy Disk',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8e969866337a65976f9',
    question:
      'What is the function of the Northbridge chipset on a motherboard?',
    correctAnswer:
      'To handle communications between the CPU, RAM, and graphics controller',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To handle power distribution',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect peripheral devices',
      },
      {
        option:
          'To handle communications between the CPU, RAM, and graphics controller',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store BIOS settings',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8e169866337a65976f6',
    question:
      'Which component inside the system unit is used for long-term storage of data?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'CPU',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cache',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8d969866337a65976f3',
    question: 'What is the purpose of expansion slots on a motherboard?',
    correctAnswer:
      'To add additional cards like graphics, sound, and network cards',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To connect the CPU and RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store BIOS settings',
      },
      {
        option:
          'To add additional cards like graphics, sound, and network cards',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide power to peripherals',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8d069866337a65976f0',
    question: 'Which component connects the CPU to the RAM?',
    correctAnswer: 'Memory bus',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Data bus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Memory bus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Power supply',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chipset',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8c869866337a65976ed',
    question:
      'What is the primary function of the heat sink in the system unit?',
    correctAnswer: 'To dissipate heat from the CPU',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide power',
      },
      {
        option: 'To dissipate heat from the CPU',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect peripherals',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8bf69866337a65976ea',
    question: 'Which component is responsible for storing the BIOS settings?',
    correctAnswer: 'CMOS',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'CMOS',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cache',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8b769866337a65976e7',
    question: 'What does PSU stand for in a computer system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Power Supply Unit',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Primary Storage Unit',
      },
      {
        option: 'Processor Support Unit',
      },
      {
        option: 'Peripheral System Unit',
      },
      {
        option: 'Power Supply Unit',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e8af69866337a65976e4',
    question:
      'Which type of memory is used for temporary storage while the computer is running?',
    correctAnswer: 'RAM',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'SSD',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e89d69866337a65976e0',
    question: 'What is the function of the motherboard in a computer?',
    correctAnswer:
      'To connect and allow communication between various components',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store data permanently',
      },
      {
        option: 'To cool down the CPU',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect and allow communication between various components',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide power to the system',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e85a69866337a65976dc',
    question:
      'Which component in the system unit is responsible for executing instructions from software applications?',
    correctAnswer: 'CPU',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Inside system unit',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk',
      },
      {
        option: 'CPU',
      },
      {
        option: 'Motherboard',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e633be4f7facabcfbc18',
    question: "What does the term 'virtual memory' refer to?",
    correctAnswer: 'Using disk storage to extend RAM capacity',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Using faster memory technology',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using disk storage to extend RAM capacity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using cloud storage',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using a separate memory chip',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e624be4f7facabcfbc15',
    question: 'Which memory technology is commonly used in USB flash drives?',
    correctAnswer: 'Flash Memory',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'DRAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'SRAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Flash Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e61dbe4f7facabcfbc12',
    question: 'Which type of ROM can be erased electrically and rewritten?',
    correctAnswer: 'EEPROM',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'PROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'EPROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'EEPROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Flash Memory',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e612be4f7facabcfbc0f',
    question:
      'Which memory is used to improve the performance of a computer by acting as a buffer between the CPU and RAM?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cache',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cache',
      },
      {
        option: 'Registers',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e609be4f7facabcfbc0c',
    question:
      "Which type of memory is typically used for a computer's main memory?",
    correctAnswer: 'DRAM',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'SRAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'DRAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'EPROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e604be4f7facabcfbc09',
    question: 'Which memory is directly accessed by the CPU?',
    correctAnswer: 'Primary Memory',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Secondary Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tertiary Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Primary Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Virtual Memory',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5fabe4f7facabcfbc06',
    question: "What does the term 'non-volatile' refer to in computer memory?",
    correctAnswer: 'Memory that retains data even when powered off',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Memory that is fast',
      },
      {
        option: 'Memory that is slow',
      },
      {
        option: 'Memory that retains data even when powered off',
      },
      {
        option: 'Memory that needs constant power',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5f3be4f7facabcfbc03',
    question: 'Which type of ROM can be reprogrammed using UV light?',
    correctAnswer: 'EPROM',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'PROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'EPROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'EEPROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Flash Memory',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5e9be4f7facabcfbc00',
    question: 'Which type of memory is fastest?',
    correctAnswer: 'Registers',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Cache',
      },
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Registers',
      },
      {
        option: 'SSD',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5e1be4f7facabcfbbfd',
    question:
      'Which type of RAM needs to be refreshed thousands of times per second?',
    correctAnswer: 'DRAM',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'SRAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'DRAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'EPROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Flash Memory',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5d8be4f7facabcfbbfa',
    question: 'What is the primary function of cache memory?',
    correctAnswer: 'To speed up access to frequently used data',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store large amounts of data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To backup data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To speed up access to frequently used data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store the operating system',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5cabe4f7facabcfbbf7',
    question: 'Which memory is used to store the BIOS settings?',
    correctAnswer: 'CMOS',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cache',
      },
      {
        option: 'CMOS',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5c2be4f7facabcfbbf4',
    question:
      'Which type of memory retains data even when the computer is turned off?',
    correctAnswer: 'ROM',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cache',
      },
      {
        option: 'Registers',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e5b8be4f7facabcfbbf1',
    question: 'What does RAM stand for?',
    correctAnswer: 'Random Access Memory',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Read Access Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Random Access Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Read-Only Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Rapid Access Memory',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e56fbe4f7facabcfbbed',
    question:
      'Which type of memory is volatile and is used for temporary storage while a computer is running?',
    correctAnswer: 'RAM',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Computer memory',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk',
      },
      {
        option: 'SSD',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e454be4f7facabcfbbe7',
    question: 'Which of the following is an example of an output device?',
    correctAnswer: 'Printer',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Keyboard',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mouse',
      },
      {
        option: 'Scanner',
      },
      {
        option: 'Printer',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e44bbe4f7facabcfbbe4',
    question: 'Which of the following is a non-volatile storage device?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Random Access Memory (RAM)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cache Memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Registers',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e425be4f7facabcfbbe0',
    question:
      'Which computer component is responsible for executing instructions from software applications?',
    correctAnswer: 'Central Processing Unit (CPU)',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Random Access Memory (RAM)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Central Processing Unit (CPU)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Motherboard',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e41dbe4f7facabcfbbdd',
    question: 'What is the primary purpose of a network interface card (NIC)?',
    correctAnswer: 'To connect a computer to a network',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To process data',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect a computer to a network',
      },
      {
        option: 'To display output',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e412be4f7facabcfbbda',
    question: 'Which of the following is an example of system software?',
    correctAnswer: 'Operating System',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Web Browser',
      },
      {
        option: 'Operating System',
      },
      {
        option: 'Word Processor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Media Player',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e40abe4f7facabcfbbd7',
    question: 'Which storage device uses flash memory to store data?',
    correctAnswer: 'Solid State Drive (SSD)',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk Drive (HDD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Solid State Drive (SSD)',
      },
      {
        option: 'CD-ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'Floppy Disk',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e402be4f7facabcfbbd4',
    question: 'What is the function of the BIOS in a computer system?',
    correctAnswer: 'To initialize and test hardware components during startup',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To manage the file system',
      },
      {
        option: 'To initialize and test hardware components during startup',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect to the internet',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide a graphical user interface',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3fabe4f7facabcfbbd1',
    question:
      'Which type of software is designed to help users perform specific tasks, such as word processing or web browsing?',
    correctAnswer: 'Application software',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'System software',
      },
      {
        option: 'Utility software',
      },
      {
        option: 'Application software',
      },
      {
        option: 'Firmware',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3f1be4f7facabcfbbce',
    question: 'What is the role of the power supply unit (PSU) in a computer?',
    correctAnswer:
      'To convert AC power to DC power for the computer components',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To provide backup power during a power outage',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store electrical energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'To convert AC power to DC power for the computer components',
      },
      {
        option: 'To regulate the temperature of the CPU',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3e9be4f7facabcfbbcb',
    question:
      'Which device converts digital signals into analog signals for transmission over telephone lines?',
    correctAnswer: 'Modem',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Router',
      },
      {
        option: 'Switch',
      },
      {
        option: 'Modem',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hub',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3e0be4f7facabcfbbc8',
    question: 'What is the function of a motherboard in a computer system?',
    correctAnswer:
      'To connect and allow communication between various components',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store data permanently',
      },
      {
        option: 'To cool down the CPU',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect and allow communication between various components',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide power to the system',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3d8be4f7facabcfbbc5',
    question:
      'Which component is responsible for storing data temporarily while a computer is running?',
    correctAnswer: 'RAM',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hard Disk Drive',
      },
      {
        option: 'RAM',
      },
      {
        option: 'ROM',
      },
      {
        option: 'SSD',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3cfbe4f7facabcfbbc2',
    question: 'What is the primary purpose of an operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'To manage hardware and software resources',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To provide security to the system',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect to the internet',
      },
      {
        option: 'To manage hardware and software resources',
      },
      {
        option: 'To create documents',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3c6be4f7facabcfbbbf',
    question: 'Which of the following is an example of an input device?',
    correctAnswer: 'Keyboard',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Monitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Printer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Keyboard',
      },
      {
        option: 'Speaker',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6674e3a3be4f7facabcfbbbc',
    question: 'What is the main function of the CPU in a computer system?',
    correctAnswer: 'To process instructions and manage the flow of information',
    class: 'Computer Science',
    chapter: 'Overview of computer system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store data permanently',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect various peripherals',
      },
      {
        option: 'To process instructions and manage the flow of information',
      },
      {
        option: 'To display output to the user',
      },
    ],
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667309daa2d15d5e018700b0',
    question: 'What is the function of an operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Manages hardware resources',
      },
      {
        option: 'Provides user interface',
      },
      {
        option: 'Manages files and directories',
      },
      {
        option: 'All of the above',
      },
    ],
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730977a2d15d5e018700ac',
    question: 'Which of the following is not an operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Oracle',
    class: 'Computer',
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Windows',
      },
      {
        option: 'Linux',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oracle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Android',
      },
    ],
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '666ebbf8c1700b0247113674',
    question:
      'Which property   states that the product of any number and 1 is the number itself?',
    correctAnswer: 'Identity property of multiplication',
    class: 'Physics',
    chapter: 'Forces & Motion',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Commutative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Associative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Distributive property',
      },
      {
        option: 'Identity property of multiplication',
      },
    ],
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '666ebbe4c1700b0247113670',
    question:
      'Which property  states that the product of any number and 1 is the number itself?',
    correctAnswer: 'Identity property of multiplication',
    class: 'Maths',
    chapter: 'Measurement',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Commutative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Associative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Distributive property',
      },
      {
        option: 'Identity property of multiplication',
      },
    ],
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '666ebbcfc1700b024711366d',
    question:
      'Which propert.  y states that the product of any number and 1 is the number itself?',
    correctAnswer: 'Identity property of multiplication',
    class: 'Maths',
    chapter: 'Vectors & Equilibrium',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Commutative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Associative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Distributive property',
      },
      {
        option: 'Identity property of multiplication',
      },
    ],
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '666eb6ed04cc214671a82d4c',
    question:
      'Which property states that the product of any number and 1 is the number itself?',
    correctAnswer: 'Identity property of multiplication',
    class: 'Maths',
    chapter: 'Chapter 1',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Commutative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Associative property of multiplication',
      },
      {
        option: 'Distributive property',
      },
      {
        option: 'Identity property of multiplication',
      },
    ],
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
];

const secondYear = [
  {
    _id: '6673c82e91285d655222cd7e',
    question:
      'Which ether is commonly used as a starting material in the production of polyurethanes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Propylene glycol ether',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethylene glycol ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propylene glycol ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butylene glycol ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glycerol ether',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c82791285d655222cd7b',
    question:
      'Which ether is commonly used in the synthesis of organic compounds?',
    correctAnswer: 'Methyl tert-butyl ether (MTBE)',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methyl tert-butyl ether (MTBE)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c82091285d655222cd78',
    question: 'Which ether is commonly used as a solvent in organic reactions?',
    correctAnswer: 'Diethyl ether',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propyl ether',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c81791285d655222cd75',
    question:
      'Which ether is used as a solvent and in the production of perfumes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ethyl ether',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propyl ether',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c80f91285d655222cd72',
    question: 'Which ether is commonly used as an anesthetic?',
    correctAnswer: 'Diethyl ether',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diethyl ether',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propyl ether',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c80891285d655222cd6f',
    question:
      'Which compound is used as a local anesthetic and derived from phenol?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lidocaine',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Aspirin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lidocaine',
      },
      {
        option: 'Morphine',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cocaine',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c80091285d655222cd6c',
    question:
      'Which phenol is commonly used as an antiseptic and disinfectant?',
    correctAnswer: 'Carbolic acid',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Salicylic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Phenol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Benzyl alcohol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbolic acid',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c7f891285d655222cd69',
    question:
      'Which alcohol is used in the synthesis of plastics and as a solvent?',
    correctAnswer: 'Butanol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butanol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c7f191285d655222cd66',
    question:
      'Which alcohol is used in the production of perfumes and as a solvent?',
    correctAnswer: 'Benzyl alcohol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isopropanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Benzyl alcohol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c7e991285d655222cd63',
    question:
      'Which alcohol is used in the production of acetone and as a solvent?',
    correctAnswer: 'Isopropanol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isopropanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butanol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c7e191285d655222cd60',
    question: 'Which alcohol is used as a disinfectant and antiseptic?',
    correctAnswer: 'Isopropyl alcohol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isopropyl alcohol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butanol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c7d991285d655222cd5d',
    question:
      'Which alcohol is commonly used as a solvent and in antifreeze products?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ethylene glycol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Glycerol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethylene glycol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propylene glycol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butylene glycol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c7d191285d655222cd5a',
    question: 'Which alcohol is commonly used in alcoholic beverages?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ethanol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butanol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c7c991285d655222cd57',
    question: 'Which alcohol is commonly known as wood alcohol?',
    correctAnswer: 'Methanol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butanol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alcohols, Phenols, and Ethers',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c78b91285d655222cd53',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used in the production of fire extinguishing agents and aerosol propellants?',
    correctAnswer: 'Bromotrifluoromethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Dichlorodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chlorofluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bromotrifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chlorodifluoromethane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c78391285d655222cd50',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used in the production of pesticides and herbicides?',
    correctAnswer: '2,4-Dichlorophenoxyacetic acid',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '2-Chlorophenol',
      },
      {
        option: '2,4-Dichlorophenoxyacetic acid',
      },
      {
        option: '2,4,6-Trichlorophenol',
      },
      {
        option: '2,4-Dinitrophenol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c77c91285d655222cd4d',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used in the production of synthetic rubber and as a precursor in organic synthesis?',
    correctAnswer: '1,3-Butadiene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1,2-Butadiene',
      },
      {
        option: '1,3-Butadiene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isobutylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cyclobutadiene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c77391285d655222cd4a',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used as a propellant in aerosol products and in the production of vinyl chloride?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chloromethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Bromomethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iodomethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Fluoromethane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c76c91285d655222cd47',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is commonly used as a solvent in organic reactions and in paint strippers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Methylene chloride',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Chloroform',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bromoform',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methylene chloride',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iodoform',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c76291285d655222cd44',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used in the production of polymers and as a refrigerant?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chloromethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Bromomethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iodomethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Fluoromethane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c75a91285d655222cd41',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used as a solvent and as a starting material in the production of pesticides?',
    correctAnswer: 'Methyl chloride',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethyl chloride',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methyl chloride',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propyl chloride',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butyl chloride',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c75391285d655222cd3e',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used in the production of refrigerants and foam blowing agents?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chlorodifluoromethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Dichlorodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bromodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chlorodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iododifluoromethane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c74b91285d655222cd3b',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is commonly used as a precursor in the synthesis of pharmaceuticals?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chloroethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Fluoroethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iodoethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloroethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bromoethane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c72791285d655222cd38',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used as a fire extinguishing agent and propellant in aerosol cans?',
    correctAnswer: 'Bromochlorodifluoromethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Dibromodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Dichlorodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chlorodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bromochlorodifluoromethane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c71e91285d655222cd35',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is commonly used as a solvent and in dry cleaning processes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Tetrachloroethylene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Bromomethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Trichloromethane (Chloroform)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Dichloromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tetrachloroethylene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c71691285d655222cd32',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used in the synthesis of pesticides and insecticides?',
    correctAnswer: 'Methyl bromide',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethyl chloride',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methyl bromide',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isopropyl iodide',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butyl fluoride',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c70e91285d655222cd2f',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is used as a local anesthetic and pain reliever?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chloroform',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methyl iodide',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloroform',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bromoethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iodoform',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c70691285d655222cd2c',
    question:
      'Which alkyl halide is commonly used as a refrigerant and known as R-12?',
    correctAnswer: 'Dichlorodifluoromethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Chloromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chloroethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Dichlorodifluoromethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chlorobenzene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c6fe91285d655222cd29',
    question: 'Which functional group is present in alkyl halides?',
    correctAnswer: 'Halogen atom (X)',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hydroxyl group (-OH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amino group (-NH2)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbonyl group (C=O)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Halogen atom (X)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Alkyl Halides',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c6d191285d655222cd26',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is used as a starting material in the production of synthetic rubber?',
    correctAnswer: 'Butadiene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Styrene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butadiene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isoprene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetylene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c6ca91285d655222cd23',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is used as a monomer in the production of PVC (polyvinyl chloride)?',
    correctAnswer: 'Vinyl chloride',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vinyl chloride',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c6c191285d655222cd20',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is commonly used as a fuel in portable stoves and heaters?',
    correctAnswer: 'Propane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c6b991285d655222cd1d',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is used as a starting material in the production of polyethylene?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ethylene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Propylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Styrene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c6b091285d655222cd1a',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is used as a propellant in aerosol sprays and as a refrigerant?',
    correctAnswer: 'Butane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c6a691285d655222cd17',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is commonly found in rubber trees and used in the production of synthetic rubber?',
    correctAnswer: 'Isoprene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Butadiene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Styrene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isoprene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetylene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c69f91285d655222cd14',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is used as a solvent in paint thinners and nail polish removers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Toluene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Benzene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Toluene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Xylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethylbenzene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c69791285d655222cd11',
    question: 'Which type of hydrocarbon is known for its aromatic nature?',
    correctAnswer: 'Arenes',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Alkanes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkenes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkynes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Arenes',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c68f91285d655222cd0e',
    question:
      'Which hydrocarbon is used in the production of synthetic fibers such as nylon?',
    correctAnswer: 'Adipic acid',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Phthalic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adipic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maleic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxalic acid',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c68791285d655222cd0b',
    question: 'Which hydrocarbon is a major component of natural rubber?',
    correctAnswer: 'Isoprene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Butadiene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Styrene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isoprene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetylene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c68091285d655222cd08',
    question: 'Which hydrocarbon is used as a refrigerant and known as R-134a?',
    correctAnswer: '1,1,1,2-Tetrafluoroethane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Chlorofluorocarbon (CFC)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethylene',
      },
      {
        option: '1,1,1,2-Tetrafluoroethane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c67791285d655222cd05',
    question: 'Which hydrocarbon is commonly found in gasoline (petrol)?',
    correctAnswer: 'Isooctane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Methane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Octane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isooctane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c67191285d655222cd02',
    question:
      'Which type of hydrocarbon contains at least one triple bond between carbon atoms?',
    correctAnswer: 'Alkynes',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Alkenes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkynes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Arenes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkanes',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c66891285d655222ccff',
    question: 'Which hydrocarbon is the major component of natural gas?',
    correctAnswer: 'Methane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Propane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Butane',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c66091285d655222ccfc',
    question:
      'Which type of hydrocarbon has only single bonds between carbon atoms?',
    correctAnswer: 'Alkanes',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Alkenes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkynes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Arenes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkanes',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Hydrocarbons',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c61b91285d655222ccf9',
    question: 'Which organic compound is commonly found in sunscreen lotions?',
    correctAnswer: 'Octinoxate',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Oxybenzone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Octinoxate',
      },
      {
        option: 'Avobenzone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Titanium dioxide',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c61391285d655222ccf6',
    question: 'Which organic compound is used in the production of rubber?',
    correctAnswer: 'Isoprene',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Butadiene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Styrene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isoprene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acrylonitrile',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c60a91285d655222ccf3',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is responsible for the bitter taste in coffee and chocolate?',
    correctAnswer: 'Caffeine',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Nicotine',
      },
      {
        option: 'Caffeine',
      },
      {
        option: 'Theobromine',
      },
      {
        option: 'Morphine',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c60291285d655222ccf0',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is used as a precursor in the production of nylon?',
    correctAnswer: 'Adipic acid',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Phthalic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adipic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maleic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxalic acid',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5f991285d655222cced',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is used as a preservative in food products?',
    correctAnswer: 'Benzoic acid',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Citric acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ascorbic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Benzoic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetic acid',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5f191285d655222ccea',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is used in the production of plastic bottles?',
    correctAnswer: 'Polyethylene terephthalate (PET)',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Polystyrene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Polyethylene terephthalate (PET)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Polypropylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Polyvinyl chloride (PVC)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5eb91285d655222cce7',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is found in aspirin and other pain relievers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Acetylsalicylic acid',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ibuprofen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Paracetamol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetylsalicylic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Naproxen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5e291285d655222cce4',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is responsible for the pungent smell of garlic and onions?',
    correctAnswer: 'Sulfur compounds',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Alcohols',
      },
      {
        option: 'Esters',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sulfur compounds',
      },
      {
        option: 'Aldehydes',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5db91285d655222cce1',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is commonly used as an antifreeze in automobile radiators?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ethylene glycol',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Propylene glycol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ethylene glycol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isopropyl alcohol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5d491285d655222ccde',
    question: 'Which functional group is present in carboxylic acids?',
    correctAnswer: 'Carboxyl group (-COOH)',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hydroxyl group (-OH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amino group (-NH2)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbonyl group (C=O)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carboxyl group (-COOH)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5c891285d655222ccdb',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is responsible for the characteristic smell of ripe fruits?',
    correctAnswer: 'Esters',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Aldehydes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ketones',
      },
      {
        option: 'Esters',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carboxylic acids',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5c091285d655222ccd8',
    question:
      'Which type of organic compound is used as a solvent in nail polish removers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Acetone',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Isopropanol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5b891285d655222ccd5',
    question: 'Which organic compound is commonly found in vinegar?',
    correctAnswer: 'Acetic acid',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lactic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Citric acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetic acid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Formic acid',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5b091285d655222ccd2',
    question:
      'Which organic compound is the primary constituent of natural gas?',
    correctAnswer: 'Methane',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ethanol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Methane',
      },
      {
        option: 'Acetylene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Benzene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c5a991285d655222cccf',
    question: 'Which functional group is present in alcohols?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hydroxyl group (-OH)',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Carbonyl group (C=O)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amino group (-NH2)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carboxyl group (-COOH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hydroxyl group (-OH)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Organic Compounds',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c57991285d655222cccc',
    question:
      'Which element is commonly used in nuclear reactors as a moderator?',
    correctAnswer: 'Thorium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Uranium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Plutonium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thorium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Protactinium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c57191285d655222ccc9',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the production of high-strength steels and alloys?',
    correctAnswer: 'Vanadium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Tungsten',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vanadium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Molybdenum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Rhenium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c56a91285d655222ccc6',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the production of glass and ceramic materials?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lanthanum',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Scandium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lanthanum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Yttrium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cerium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c56291285d655222ccc3',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the manufacture of superconductors for magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) machines?',
    correctAnswer: 'Yttrium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lanthanum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Yttrium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Dysprosium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thulium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c55b91285d655222ccc0',
    question: 'Which element is commonly used in magnets and electric motors?',
    correctAnswer: 'Iron',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Cobalt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nickel',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iron',
      },
      {
        option: 'Manganese',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c55491285d655222ccbd',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the production of flat-panel displays and solar cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Indium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Gallium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Indium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thallium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bismuth',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c54b91285d655222ccba',
    question:
      'Which element is commonly used in catalysts for petroleum refining processes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Platinum',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Palladium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iridium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Platinum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gold',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c54391285d655222ccb7',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the production of high-strength alloys in aerospace applications?',
    correctAnswer: 'Tantalum',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Niobium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tantalum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ruthenium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Rhodium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c53b91285d655222ccb4',
    question:
      'Which actinide element is commonly used in smoke detectors due to its radioactivity?',
    correctAnswer: 'Americium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thorium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Uranium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Americium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Curium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c53291285d655222ccb1',
    question:
      'Which element is known for its use in nuclear reactors as a neutron absorber?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cadmium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Mercury',
      },
      {
        option: 'Zinc',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cadmium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lead',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c52a91285d655222ccae',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the production of jet engine components due to its high melting point?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hafnium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Tungsten',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hafnium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Rhenium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Osmium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c52291285d655222ccab',
    question: 'Which lanthanide element is commonly used in magnets?',
    correctAnswer: 'Neodymium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lanthanum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Neodymium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Europium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ytterbium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c51b91285d655222cca8',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the manufacture of titanium dioxide, a white pigment?',
    correctAnswer: 'Titanium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Zirconium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tantalum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Titanium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vanadium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c51391285d655222cca5',
    question:
      'Which element is commonly used in stainless steel due to its corrosion resistance?',
    correctAnswer: 'Chromium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Manganese',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cobalt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chromium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nickel',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c50a91285d655222cca2',
    question:
      'Which series of elements is found between groups 2 and 3 in the periodic table?',
    correctAnswer: 'Transition metals',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Alkali metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkaline earth metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Halogens',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transition metals',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'd and f-Block Elements',
    date: '2024-06-20',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c3da91285d655222cc9f',
    question:
      'Which group of elements includes lithium, sodium, potassium, rubidium, cesium, and francium?',
    correctAnswer: 'Alkali metals',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Noble gases',
      },
      {
        option: 'Halogens',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkali metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transition metals',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c3d291285d655222cc9c',
    question: 'Which element is known for its role in DNA and RNA molecules?',
    correctAnswer: 'Phosphorus',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Boron',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbon',
      },
      {
        option: 'Phosphorus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sulfur',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c3c991285d655222cc99',
    question:
      'Which element is used in the manufacture of ammonia and fertilizers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Nitrogen',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Phosphorus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sulfur',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nitrogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxygen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c3c191285d655222cc96',
    question:
      'Which element is essential for the formation of bones and teeth in humans?',
    correctAnswer: 'Calcium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Iron',
      },
      {
        option: 'Copper',
      },
      {
        option: 'Calcium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Zinc',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c3b991285d655222cc93',
    question:
      'Which group of elements includes beryllium, magnesium, calcium, strontium, barium, and radium?',
    correctAnswer: 'Alkaline earth metals',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Noble gases',
      },
      {
        option: 'Halogens',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkaline earth metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transition metals',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c3b091285d655222cc90',
    question:
      'Which element has the atomic number 6 and is the basis of organic chemistry?',
    correctAnswer: 'Carbon',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Boron',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nitrogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbon',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxygen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c3a491285d655222cc8d',
    question:
      'Which element is known for its semiconductor properties and is widely used in electronics?',
    correctAnswer: 'Silicon',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Aluminum',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sulfur',
      },
      {
        option: 'Silicon',
      },
      {
        option: 'Phosphorus',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c39b91285d655222cc8a',
    question: 'Which element is commonly found in table salt?',
    correctAnswer: 'Sodium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Potassium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Calcium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sodium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Magnesium',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c39391285d655222cc87',
    question:
      'Which group of elements includes fluorine, chlorine, bromine, iodine, and astatine?',
    correctAnswer: 'Halogens',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Alkali metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkaline earth metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transition metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Halogens',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c38b91285d655222cc84',
    question: "Which element forms the majority of Earth's atmosphere?",
    correctAnswer: 'Nitrogen',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Oxygen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbon',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nitrogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hydrogen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c38091285d655222cc81',
    question:
      'Which element is essential for plant growth and is often found in fertilizers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Phosphorus',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Sulfur',
      },
      {
        option: 'Chlorine',
      },
      {
        option: 'Phosphorus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Boron',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c37891285d655222cc7e',
    question: 'Which group of elements is highly reactive with water?',
    correctAnswer: 'Alkali metals',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Noble gases',
      },
      {
        option: 'Halogens',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkali metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transition metals',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c37291285d655222cc7b',
    question: 'Which element is commonly used in batteries?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lithium',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Boron',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbon',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lithium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxygen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c36891285d655222cc78',
    question: 'Which element is a liquid at room temperature?',
    correctAnswer: 'Mercury',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Sodium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Potassium',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mercury',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lead',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c36091285d655222cc75',
    question:
      'Which group of elements includes helium, neon, argon, krypton, xenon, and radon?',
    correctAnswer: 'Noble gases',
    class: 'Chemistry',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Alkali metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alkaline earth metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transition metals',
      },
      {
        option: 'Noble gases',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 's and p-Block Elements',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c32491285d655222cc72',
    question:
      'What is the term for the process of an electron transitioning from a higher energy state to a lower energy state?',
    correctAnswer: 'Relaxation',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ionization',
      },
      {
        option: 'Excitation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Emission',
      },
      {
        option: 'Relaxation',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c31391285d655222cc6f',
    question:
      'Which series in the hydrogen atom spectrum lies in the visible region?',
    correctAnswer: 'Balmer series',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Lyman series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Paschen series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Brackett series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Balmer series',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c30791285d655222cc6c',
    question:
      'What is the term for the minimum energy required to remove an electron from an atom in its ground state?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ionization energy',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Binding energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Excitation energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ionization energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Photon energy',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2fe91285d655222cc69',
    question:
      'Which series in the hydrogen atom spectrum lies in the infrared region?',
    correctAnswer: 'Paschen series',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Balmer series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lyman series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Brackett series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Paschen series',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2f491285d655222cc66',
    question:
      'What is the term for the distance between adjacent spectral lines?',
    correctAnswer: 'Wavelength',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Frequency',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wavelength',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amplitude',
      },
      {
        option: 'Phase',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2ec91285d655222cc63',
    question:
      'Which law states that the square of the frequency of a spectral line is proportional to the reciprocal of the square of the integer numbers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Rydberg formula',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Planck's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Bohr's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Einstein's law",
      },
      {
        option: 'Rydberg formula',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2e291285d655222cc60',
    question:
      'Which term describes the emission of light from an excited atom when it returns to a lower energy state?',
    correctAnswer: 'Emission',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Reflection',
      },
      {
        option: 'Refraction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Absorption',
      },
      {
        option: 'Emission',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2d991285d655222cc5d',
    question:
      'What is the term for the difference in energy between two atomic energy levels?',
    correctAnswer: 'Energy gap',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Photon energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Quantum energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'Energy gap',
      },
      {
        option: 'Potential energy',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2d191285d655222cc5a',
    question: 'Which scientist formulated the Bohr model of the hydrogen atom?',
    correctAnswer: 'Niels Bohr',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Max Planck',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ernest Rutherford',
      },
      {
        option: 'Albert Einstein',
      },
      {
        option: 'Niels Bohr',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2ca91285d655222cc57',
    question:
      'What phenomenon occurs when an atom absorbs a photon and moves to a higher energy level?',
    correctAnswer: 'Absorption',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Reflection',
      },
      {
        option: 'Refraction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Absorption',
      },
      {
        option: 'Emission',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2c291285d655222cc54',
    question:
      'Which series in the hydrogen atom spectrum lies in the ultraviolet region?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lyman series',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Balmer series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Paschen series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Brackett series',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lyman series',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2ba91285d655222cc51',
    question: 'What is the term for the smallest unit of light?',
    correctAnswer: 'Photon',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Electron',
      },
      {
        option: 'Proton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Photon',
      },
      {
        option: 'Neutron',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2b191285d655222cc4e',
    question:
      'Which scientist discovered that atoms emit and absorb light at specific wavelengths?',
    correctAnswer: 'Johannes Rydberg',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Max Planck',
      },
      {
        option: 'Niels Bohr',
      },
      {
        option: 'Albert Einstein',
      },
      {
        option: 'Johannes Rydberg',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2a891285d655222cc4b',
    question: 'Which type of spectra consists of discrete lines?',
    correctAnswer: 'Line spectra',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Continuous spectra',
      },
      {
        option: 'Emission spectra',
      },
      {
        option: 'Absorption spectra',
      },
      {
        option: 'Line spectra',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c2a091285d655222cc48',
    question: 'Who proposed the planetary model of the atom?',
    correctAnswer: 'Niels Bohr',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ernest Rutherford',
      },
      {
        option: 'Max Planck',
      },
      {
        option: 'Albert Einstein',
      },
      {
        option: 'Niels Bohr',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Atomic Spectra',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c27491285d655222cc45',
    question: 'What is the function of a transformer in electronics?',
    correctAnswer: 'To step up or step down AC voltage',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To convert AC to DC',
      },
      {
        option: 'To amplify signals',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'To step up or step down AC voltage',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c26c91285d655222cc42',
    question:
      'Which component is used to protect electronic circuits from voltage spikes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Diode',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Fuse',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Resistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diode',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c26491285d655222cc3f',
    question: 'Which type of capacitor has a variable capacitance?',
    correctAnswer: 'Variable capacitor',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Polarized capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ceramic capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tantalum capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Variable capacitor',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c25d91285d655222cc3c',
    question:
      'Which electronic component is used to change the amplitude of a signal?',
    correctAnswer: 'Amplifier',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Oscillator',
      },
      {
        option: 'Filter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transformer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amplifier',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c25591285d655222cc39',
    question: 'What is the purpose of a resistor in an electronic circuit?',
    correctAnswer: 'To limit current or divide voltage',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To amplify signals',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store charge',
      },
      {
        option: 'To switch circuits',
      },
      {
        option: 'To limit current or divide voltage',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c24d91285d655222cc36',
    question: 'Which type of logic gate performs the operation of logical AND?',
    correctAnswer: 'AND gate',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'OR gate',
      },
      {
        option: 'NOT gate',
      },
      {
        option: 'NAND gate',
      },
      {
        option: 'AND gate',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c24691285d655222cc33',
    question:
      'Which electronic component is used to store binary data in digital systems?',
    correctAnswer: 'Flip-flop',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Resistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Flip-flop',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c23f91285d655222cc30',
    question: 'What is the purpose of an oscillator in electronics?',
    correctAnswer: 'To generate an AC signal',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To regulate voltage',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'To filter noise',
      },
      {
        option: 'To generate an AC signal',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c23891285d655222cc2d',
    question:
      'Which electronic component is used to amplify signals in electronic circuits?',
    correctAnswer: 'Transistor',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Resistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transistor',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c23191285d655222cc2a',
    question: "What does the acronym 'IC' stand for in electronics?",
    correctAnswer: 'Integrated Circuit',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Insulated Capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inverter Circuit',
      },
      {
        option: 'Integrated Capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Integrated Circuit',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c22991285d655222cc27',
    question: 'Which type of diode emits light when forward biased?',
    correctAnswer: 'Light-emitting diode (LED)',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Zener diode',
      },
      {
        option: 'Schottky diode',
      },
      {
        option: 'Photodiode',
      },
      {
        option: 'Light-emitting diode (LED)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c22291285d655222cc24',
    question: 'What is the function of a diode in an electronic circuit?',
    correctAnswer: 'Allows current to flow in one direction only',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Amplifies the signal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Filters the signal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Generates a signal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Allows current to flow in one direction only',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c21a91285d655222cc21',
    question:
      'Which electronic component stores electrical energy in an electric field?',
    correctAnswer: 'Capacitor',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Resistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Diode',
      },
      {
        option: 'Capacitor',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c21291285d655222cc1e',
    question: 'What is the fundamental unit of digital electronics?',
    correctAnswer: 'Bit',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Byte',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ohm',
      },
      {
        option: 'Volt',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bit',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c20691285d655222cc1b',
    question: 'Which of the following is a semiconductor device?',
    correctAnswer: 'Transistor',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Resistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transistor',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electronics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c1d491285d655222cc18',
    question:
      'In an AC circuit, what is the phase relationship between voltage and current in a purely capacitive circuit?',
    correctAnswer: 'Current leads voltage by 90 degrees',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Voltage leads current by 90 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: 'Voltage and current are in phase',
      },
      {
        option: 'Current lags voltage by 90 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: 'Current leads voltage by 90 degrees',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c1cb91285d655222cc15',
    question: 'What is the unit of measurement for inductive reactance?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ohm (Ω)',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Henry (H)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Farad (F)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tesla (T)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ohm (Ω)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c1c291285d655222cc12',
    question: 'Which type of AC circuit consists of only resistive elements?',
    correctAnswer: 'Purely resistive circuit',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'RL circuit',
      },
      {
        option: 'LC circuit',
      },
      {
        option: 'RC circuit',
      },
      {
        option: 'Purely resistive circuit',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c1bc91285d655222cc0f',
    question:
      'What happens to the reactance of a capacitor in an AC circuit if the frequency of the source decreases?',
    correctAnswer: 'It increases',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It decreases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It remains the same',
      },
      {
        option: 'It becomes zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'It increases',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c1b291285d655222cc0c',
    question:
      'Which law states that the sum of currents entering a junction in an AC circuit is equal to the sum of currents leaving the junction?',
    correctAnswer: "Kirchhoff's current law (KCL)",
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Ohm's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Kirchhoff's voltage law (KVL)",
      },
      {
        option: "Faraday's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Kirchhoff's current law (KCL)",
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c1aa91285d655222cc09',
    question:
      'In an AC circuit, what is the relationship between voltage (V), current (I), and impedance (Z)?',
    correctAnswer: 'V = I × Z',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'V = I / Z',
      },
      {
        option: 'V = I + Z',
      },
      {
        option: 'V = I × Z',
      },
      {
        option: 'V = I - Z',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c1a391285d655222cc06',
    question: 'Which device is used to measure AC voltage?',
    correctAnswer: 'AC voltmeter',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'DC voltmeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ammeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'Multimeter',
      },
      {
        option: 'AC voltmeter',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c19991285d655222cc03',
    question:
      'In a series RL circuit with AC, what happens to the impedance if the frequency of the source increases?',
    correctAnswer: 'It increases',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It decreases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It remains the same',
      },
      {
        option: 'It becomes zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'It increases',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c19191285d655222cc00',
    question:
      'Which component in an AC circuit leads the current waveform by 90 degrees?',
    correctAnswer: 'Inductor',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Resistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transformer',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductor',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c18a91285d655222cbfd',
    question: 'In an AC circuit, the power factor is defined as the ratio of:',
    correctAnswer: 'Real power to apparent power',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Real power to reactive power',
      },
      {
        option: 'Apparent power to reactive power',
      },
      {
        option: 'Apparent power to real power',
      },
      {
        option: 'Real power to apparent power',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c18391285d655222cbfa',
    question:
      'What is the phase difference between current and voltage in a purely resistive AC circuit?',
    correctAnswer: 'Zero degrees',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '90 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '180 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '45 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: 'Zero degrees',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c17a91285d655222cbf7',
    question:
      'Which parameter is used to measure the opposition to the flow of AC current in a circuit?',
    correctAnswer: 'Impedance',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Resistance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Capacitance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductance',
      },
      {
        option: 'Impedance',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c17491285d655222cbf4',
    question: 'What is the frequency of AC mains in most countries?',
    correctAnswer: '50 Hz or 60 Hz',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '100 Hz',
      },
      {
        option: '50 Hz or 60 Hz',
      },
      {
        option: '10 Hz',
      },
      {
        option: '120 Hz',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c16b91285d655222cbf1',
    question:
      'In an AC circuit, the current and voltage vary with time. Which of the following waveforms represents a pure AC voltage?',
    correctAnswer: 'Sine wave',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Square wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Triangle wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pulse wave',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sine wave',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c16391285d655222cbee',
    question: 'What is the full form of AC in AC circuits?',
    correctAnswer: 'Alternating Current',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Applied Current',
      },
      {
        option: 'Amplified Current',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alternating Current',
      },
      {
        option: 'Average Current',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'AC Circuits',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c13a91285d655222cbeb',
    question: 'Which material has very high magnetic permeability?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ferromagnetic material',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Diamagnetic material',
      },
      {
        option: 'Paramagnetic material',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ferromagnetic material',
      },
      {
        option: 'Non-magnetic material',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c13291285d655222cbe8',
    question:
      'Which law states that the electromotive force (emf) induced in a circuit is equal to the rate of change of magnetic flux through the circuit?',
    correctAnswer: "Lenz's law",
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Gauss's law for electricity",
      },
      {
        option: "Ampère's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Lenz's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Faraday's law of electromagnetic induction",
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c0d391285d655222cbdd',
    question: 'What does the right-hand rule for magnetic fields determine?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The direction of the magnetic field around a current-carrying conductor',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'The magnitude of the magnetic field around a current-carrying conductor',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The direction of the electric field around a current-carrying conductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'The direction of the induced current in a conductor',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The direction of the magnetic field around a current-carrying conductor',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c0c591285d655222cbda',
    question:
      'The force experienced by a current-carrying conductor in a magnetic field is maximum when the angle between the current and the magnetic field is:',
    correctAnswer: '90 degrees',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '0 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '45 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '180 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '90 degrees',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c0bb91285d655222cbd7',
    question: 'What is the unit of magnetic flux?',
    correctAnswer: 'Weber (Wb)',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Tesla (T)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Henry (H)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Weber (Wb)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Farad (F)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c0b391285d655222cbd4',
    question:
      'What is the direction of the magnetic field inside a current-carrying circular loop?',
    correctAnswer: 'Along the axis perpendicular to the plane of the loop',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Along the plane of the loop',
      },
      {
        option: 'Toward the center of the loop',
      },
      {
        option: 'Away from the center of the loop',
      },
      {
        option: 'Along the axis perpendicular to the plane of the loop',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c0ac91285d655222cbd1',
    question:
      "Which device is used to convert mechanical energy into electrical energy based on Faraday's law of electromagnetic induction?",
    correctAnswer: 'Generator',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Capacitor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Transistor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Generator',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c0a491285d655222cbce',
    question:
      'The magnetic field due to a long straight current-carrying conductor decreases with increasing distance according to which law?',
    correctAnswer: 'Inverse square law',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Ohm's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Coulomb's law",
      },
      {
        option: 'Inverse square law',
      },
      {
        option: "Gauss's law for electricity",
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c09b91285d655222cbcb',
    question:
      'Which law states that the magnetic field induced in a closed loop is directly proportional to the rate of change of magnetic flux through the loop?',
    correctAnswer: "Faraday's law of electromagnetic induction",
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "Ampère's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Gauss's law for magnetism",
      },
      {
        option: "Ohm's law",
      },
      {
        option: "Faraday's law of electromagnetic induction",
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c09391285d655222cbc8',
    question:
      'The magnetic force experienced by a charge moving in a magnetic field is maximum when the direction of motion is:',
    correctAnswer: 'Perpendicular to the magnetic field',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Along the magnetic field',
      },
      {
        option: 'Opposite to the magnetic field',
      },
      {
        option: 'At an angle of 45 degrees to the magnetic field',
      },
      {
        option: 'Perpendicular to the magnetic field',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c08c91285d655222cbc5',
    question: 'The magnetic field inside a long solenoid carrying current is:',
    correctAnswer: 'Uniform and parallel to the axis of the solenoid',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maximum at the center',
      },
      {
        option: 'Circular around the solenoid',
      },
      {
        option: 'Uniform and parallel to the axis of the solenoid',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c08491285d655222cbc2',
    question:
      'Which of the following phenomena does NOT demonstrate electromagnetic induction?',
    correctAnswer: 'Photoelectric effect',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Transformers',
      },
      {
        option: 'Generators',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inductors',
      },
      {
        option: 'Photoelectric effect',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c07a91285d655222cbbf',
    question:
      "According to Lenz's law, the direction of an induced current in a circuit is such that it:",
    correctAnswer: 'Opposes the change in magnetic flux',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Enhances the change in magnetic flux',
      },
      {
        option: 'Does not affect the magnetic flux',
      },
      {
        option: 'Creates a new magnetic flux',
      },
      {
        option: 'Opposes the change in magnetic flux',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c06f91285d655222cbbc',
    question:
      'A current-carrying wire experiences a force in a magnetic field. This force is maximum when the angle between the wire and the magnetic field is:',
    correctAnswer: '90 degrees',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '0 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '45 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '180 degrees',
      },
      {
        option: '90 degrees',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c06791285d655222cbb9',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of magnetic field strength?',
    correctAnswer: 'Tesla (T)',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Weber (Wb)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ohm (Ω)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tesla (T)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Henry (H)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electromagnetism',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c03d91285d655222cbb6',
    question: 'What is the permittivity of free space (ε₀)?',
    correctAnswer: '8.85 × 10^-12 F/m',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1/ε₀',
      },
      {
        option: '8.85 × 10^-12 F/m',
      },
      {
        option: '4πε₀',
      },
      {
        option: '√ε₀',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c03691285d655222cbb3',
    question:
      'What is the force experienced by a charge Q moving with velocity v in a magnetic field B?',
    correctAnswer: 'QvB sinθ',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'QvB',
      },
      {
        option: 'QvB cosθ',
      },
      {
        option: 'Q/B',
      },
      {
        option: 'QvB sinθ',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c02e91285d655222cbb0',
    question:
      'What is the relationship between electric field (E) and electric potential (V)?',
    correctAnswer: 'E = -∇V',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'E = V/d',
      },
      {
        option: 'E = ∇V',
      },
      {
        option: 'E = kQ/r^2',
      },
      {
        option: 'E = -∇V',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c02691285d655222cbad',
    question:
      'What happens to the capacitance of a parallel plate capacitor if the distance between the plates is increased?',
    correctAnswer: 'It decreases',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It increases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It remains the same',
      },
      {
        option: 'It depends on the area of the plates',
      },
      {
        option: 'It decreases',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c01f91285d655222cbaa',
    question: 'In which situation is the electric potential zero?',
    correctAnswer: 'At infinity',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'At the center of a charged sphere',
      },
      {
        option: 'At the surface of a charged conductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inside a uniformly charged sphere',
      },
      {
        option: 'At infinity',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c01291285d655222cba7',
    question:
      "What does Gauss's law state about the total electric flux through a closed surface?",
    correctAnswer:
      'It is equal to the net charge enclosed by the surface divided by the permittivity of free space',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It is zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'It depends on the shape of the surface',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is constant',
      },
      {
        option:
          'It is equal to the net charge enclosed by the surface divided by the permittivity of free space',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c00a91285d655222cba4',
    question:
      'Which statement correctly describes the electric potential energy of a system of charges?',
    correctAnswer:
      'It is the work required to bring the charges from infinity to their current positions',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It depends on the charge of the particles',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is always zero',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is the work required to separate the charges',
      },
      {
        option:
          'It is the work required to bring the charges from infinity to their current positions',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673c00291285d655222cba1',
    question:
      'What is the electric potential due to a point charge at a distance r?',
    correctAnswer: 'kQ/r',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'kQ',
      },
      {
        option: 'Q/r',
      },
      {
        option: 'Q^2/r',
      },
      {
        option: 'kQ/r',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bff591285d655222cb9e',
    question: 'What is the electric potential at a point in an electric field?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Work done per unit charge in bringing a test charge from infinity to that point',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Electric charge density at that point',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electric field strength at that point',
      },
      {
        option: 'Potential energy of the charges at that point',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Work done per unit charge in bringing a test charge from infinity to that point',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bfe891285d655222cb9b',
    question:
      'What happens to the magnitude of the electric field between two point charges if the distance between them is doubled?',
    correctAnswer: 'It decreases by a factor of 4',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It remains the same',
      },
      {
        option: 'It decreases by half',
      },
      {
        option: 'It decreases by a factor of 4',
      },
      {
        option: 'It increases by a factor of 2',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bfe191285d655222cb98',
    question: 'Which of the following statements about conductors is true?',
    correctAnswer: 'Electric charges reside on the surface of a conductor',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Conductors cannot hold electric charge',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electric charges reside inside a conductor',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Electric charges are evenly distributed throughout a conductor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electric charges reside on the surface of a conductor',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bfda91285d655222cb95',
    question:
      'When a charged particle moves in a uniform electric field, the work done by the electric field on the particle depends on:',
    correctAnswer: 'The displacement of the particle',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The charge of the particle',
      },
      {
        option: 'The speed of the particle',
      },
      {
        option: 'The direction of the electric field',
      },
      {
        option: 'The displacement of the particle',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bfd191285d655222cb92',
    question:
      'The electric field at a point due to a positive charge is directed:',
    correctAnswer: 'Away from the charge',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Toward the charge',
      },
      {
        option: 'Perpendicular to the charge',
      },
      {
        option: 'At an angle to the charge',
      },
      {
        option: 'Away from the charge',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bfca91285d655222cb8f',
    question:
      'Two positive point charges are brought close to each other. What happens to the force between them?',
    correctAnswer: 'It decreases',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It increases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It remains the same',
      },
      {
        option: 'It decreases',
      },
      {
        option: 'It depends on their masses',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bfc091285d655222cb8c',
    question: 'What is the SI unit of electric charge?',
    correctAnswer: 'Coulomb (C)',
    class: 'Physics',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ohm (Ω)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ampere (A)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Volt (V)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Coulomb (C)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Electrostatics',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf7091285d655222cb89',
    question: 'Which hormone stimulates the production of red blood cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Erythropoietin',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Calcitonin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Aldosterone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Erythropoietin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Insulin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf6991285d655222cb86',
    question:
      'Which hormone is involved in the regulation of sleep-wake cycles?',
    correctAnswer: 'Melatonin',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Adrenaline',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cortisol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Melatonin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thyroxine (T4)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf6191285d655222cb83',
    question:
      'Which hormone is responsible for promoting the development and maintenance of male secondary sexual characteristics?',
    correctAnswer: 'Testosterone',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Estrogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Progesterone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testosterone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxytocin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf5891285d655222cb80',
    question:
      'Which hormone is responsible for stimulating the release of glucagon and insulin from the pancreas?',
    correctAnswer: 'Glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP-1)',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Glucagon-like peptide 1 (GLP-1)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thyroxine (T4)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thyrotropin-releasing hormone (TRH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adrenaline',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf4e91285d655222cb7d',
    question:
      'Which hormone is involved in the regulation of blood pressure and sodium-potassium balance?',
    correctAnswer: 'Aldosterone',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Insulin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Aldosterone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glucagon',
      },
      {
        option: 'Prolactin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf4691285d655222cb7a',
    question:
      'Which hormone stimulates the growth and development of ovarian follicles in females and sperm production in males?',
    correctAnswer: 'Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Luteinizing hormone (LH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Growth hormone (GH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thyroxine (T4)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf3e91285d655222cb77',
    question:
      'Which hormone regulates metabolism and is produced by the thyroid gland?',
    correctAnswer: 'Thyroxine (T4)',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thyrotropin-releasing hormone (TRH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thyroxine (T4)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Calcitonin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf3691285d655222cb74',
    question:
      'Which hormone stimulates uterine contractions during childbirth and milk ejection during breastfeeding?',
    correctAnswer: 'Oxytocin',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Estrogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Progesterone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxytocin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testosterone',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf2e91285d655222cb71',
    question:
      'Which hormone is responsible for promoting water retention by the kidneys?',
    correctAnswer: 'Antidiuretic hormone (ADH)',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Aldosterone',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adrenaline',
      },
      {
        option: 'Antidiuretic hormone (ADH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glucagon',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf2491285d655222cb6e',
    question:
      'Which gland produces melatonin, a hormone involved in sleep regulation?',
    correctAnswer: 'Pineal gland',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thyroid gland',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pituitary gland',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adrenal gland',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pineal gland',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf1d91285d655222cb6b',
    question: "Which hormone is known as the 'stress hormone'?",
    correctAnswer: 'Cortisol',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Adrenaline',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cortisol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxytocin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Melatonin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf1291285d655222cb68',
    question: 'Which gland produces insulin and glucagon?',
    correctAnswer: 'Pancreas',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thyroid gland',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pituitary gland',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pancreas',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adrenal gland',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf0b91285d655222cb65',
    question: 'Which hormone is responsible for regulating blood sugar levels?',
    correctAnswer: 'Insulin',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thyroxine',
      },
      {
        option: 'Insulin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adrenaline',
      },
      {
        option: 'Progesterone',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bf0291285d655222cb62',
    question: 'Which hormone regulates calcium levels in the blood and bones?',
    correctAnswer: 'Parathyroid hormone (PTH)',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Insulin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Parathyroid hormone (PTH)',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cortisol',
      },
      {
        option: 'Estrogen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673befb91285d655222cb5f',
    question:
      'Which of the following glands is considered the master gland of the endocrine system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Pituitary gland',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Thyroid gland',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adrenal gland',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pancreas',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pituitary gland',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Chemical Coordination',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bed391285d655222cb5c',
    question: 'In flowering plants, what part develops into a fruit?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ovary',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Stamen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Petal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ovary',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sepal',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673becc91285d655222cb59',
    question: 'Which plant structure is responsible for producing pollen?',
    correctAnswer: 'Anther',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Stigma',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ovary',
      },
      {
        option: 'Anther',
      },
      {
        option: 'Style',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bec391285d655222cb56',
    question: 'What is parthenogenesis?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A form of asexual reproduction where an egg develops without fertilization',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Sexual reproduction involving multiple partners',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A form of asexual reproduction where an egg develops without fertilization',
      },
      {
        option: 'The development of offspring from unfertilized eggs',
      },
      {
        option: 'The fusion of two different species to form a hybrid',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bebc91285d655222cb53',
    question: 'Which of the following organisms reproduces through budding?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hydra',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hydra',
      },
      {
        option: 'Earthworm',
      },
      {
        option: 'Frog',
      },
      {
        option: 'Fish',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673beb491285d655222cb50',
    question: 'What is the role of the placenta in mammalian reproduction?',
    correctAnswer: 'To provide nutrients and oxygen to the developing embryo',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To produce gametes',
      },
      {
        option: 'To remove waste from the embryo',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide nutrients and oxygen to the developing embryo',
      },
      {
        option: 'To trigger labor and delivery',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673beac91285d655222cb4d',
    question: 'In humans, where does fertilization typically occur?',
    correctAnswer: 'Fallopian tube',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ovary',
      },
      {
        option: 'Uterus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Fallopian tube',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vagina',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bea391285d655222cb4a',
    question: 'Which of the following is an example of a gamete?',
    correctAnswer: 'Sperm',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Sperm',
      },
      {
        option: 'Zygote',
      },
      {
        option: 'Embryo',
      },
      {
        option: 'Spore',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be9a91285d655222cb47',
    question:
      'In which type of reproduction does an organism reproduce without the involvement of another organism?',
    correctAnswer: 'Asexual reproduction',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Sexual reproduction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Asexual reproduction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cross-pollination',
      },
      {
        option: 'Conjugation',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be9291285d655222cb44',
    question: 'Which process leads to the production of gametes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Meiosis',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Mitosis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Meiosis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Binary fission',
      },
      {
        option: 'Budding',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be7e91285d655222cb41',
    question: 'What is the term for the union of sperm and egg?',
    correctAnswer: 'Fertilization',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Mitosis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Fertilization',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gametogenesis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Germination',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be6c91285d655222cb3e',
    question: 'In plants, what is the male reproductive organ called?',
    correctAnswer: 'Stamen',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Stamen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carpel',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sepal',
      },
      {
        option: 'Petal',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be6491285d655222cb3b',
    question: 'Which of the following is a form of asexual reproduction?',
    correctAnswer: 'Binary fission',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Fertilization',
      },
      {
        option: 'Binary fission',
      },
      {
        option: 'Meiosis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cross-pollination',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be5b91285d655222cb38',
    question: 'What is the main advantage of sexual reproduction?',
    correctAnswer: 'Genetic diversity',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Genetic diversity',
      },
      {
        option: 'Faster reproduction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Clonal offspring',
      },
      {
        option: 'Requires only one parent',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be5391285d655222cb35',
    question: 'Which type of reproduction involves the fusion of gametes?',
    correctAnswer: 'Sexual reproduction',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Asexual reproduction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sexual reproduction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Binary fission',
      },
      {
        option: 'Budding',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be4c91285d655222cb32',
    question: 'What is the primary purpose of reproduction?',
    correctAnswer: 'To ensure the continuation of a species',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To provide energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'To ensure the continuation of a species',
      },
      {
        option: 'To improve adaptation',
      },
      {
        option: 'To regulate metabolism',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Reproduction',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be2291285d655222cb2f',
    question: 'What is a mutation?',
    correctAnswer: 'A change in the DNA sequence',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A change in the DNA sequence',
      },
      {
        option: 'The expression of a gene',
      },
      {
        option: 'The inheritance of traits from parents',
      },
      {
        option: 'The physical manifestation of a trait',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be1a91285d655222cb2c',
    question: 'What does it mean if an organism is described as diploid?',
    correctAnswer: 'It has two sets of chromosomes',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It has one set of chromosomes',
      },
      {
        option: 'It has two sets of chromosomes',
      },
      {
        option: 'It has three sets of chromosomes',
      },
      {
        option: 'It has multiple alleles for a single gene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be1291285d655222cb29',
    question: 'What is a sex-linked trait?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A trait associated with a gene that is carried on one of the sex chromosomes',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A trait that affects only males',
      },
      {
        option: 'A trait that affects only females',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A trait associated with a gene that is carried on one of the sex chromosomes',
      },
      {
        option: 'A trait that is not inherited but acquired during life',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be0b91285d655222cb26',
    question: 'What is polygenic inheritance?',
    correctAnswer: 'A single trait controlled by two or more genes',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A single gene controlling multiple traits',
      },
      {
        option: 'A single trait controlled by two or more genes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Inheritance of traits through the mitochondrial DNA',
      },
      {
        option: 'Traits controlled by non-genetic factors',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673be0391285d655222cb23',
    question: 'What is incomplete dominance?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A situation where the heterozygous phenotype is an intermediate of the two homozygous phenotypes',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'One allele completely masks the effect of another',
      },
      {
        option: 'Both alleles contribute equally to the phenotype',
      },
      {
        option: 'The alleles blend to form an intermediate phenotype',
      },
      {
        option: 'Both alleles are harmful',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bdfa91285d655222cb20',
    question: 'What is codominance?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A situation in which both alleles contribute equally to the phenotype',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'One allele completely masks the effect of another',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A situation in which both alleles contribute equally to the phenotype',
      },
      {
        option: 'Both alleles are harmful',
      },
      {
        option: 'The alleles blend to form an intermediate phenotype',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bdf391285d655222cb1d',
    question: 'What is a Punnett square used for?',
    correctAnswer: 'To predict the probability of certain traits in offspring',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To sequence DNA',
      },
      {
        option: 'To predict the probability of certain traits in offspring',
      },
      {
        option: 'To map the chromosomes of an organism',
      },
      {
        option: 'To determine the age of fossils',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bdeb91285d655222cb1a',
    question: 'What is the genotype?',
    correctAnswer: 'The genetic makeup of an organism',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The physical appearance of an organism',
      },
      {
        option: 'The genetic makeup of an organism',
      },
      {
        option: 'The process of passing traits from parents to offspring',
      },
      {
        option: 'The study of evolutionary relationships',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bde291285d655222cb17',
    question: 'What is the phenotype?',
    correctAnswer: 'The physical appearance or expression of a trait',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The genetic makeup of an organism',
      },
      {
        option: 'The physical appearance or expression of a trait',
      },
      {
        option: 'The number of chromosomes in a cell',
      },
      {
        option: 'The sequence of DNA in a gene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bdd991285d655222cb14',
    question: 'What is heterozygous?',
    correctAnswer: 'Having two different alleles for a particular gene',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Having two identical alleles for a particular gene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Having two different alleles for a particular gene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Having three alleles for a particular gene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Having no alleles for a particular gene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bdd091285d655222cb11',
    question: 'What is homozygous?',
    correctAnswer: 'Having two identical alleles for a particular gene',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Having two different alleles for a particular gene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Having two identical alleles for a particular gene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Having three alleles for a particular gene',
      },
      {
        option: 'Having no alleles for a particular gene',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bdc991285d655222cb0e',
    question:
      'What is the difference between a dominant and a recessive allele?',
    correctAnswer: 'A dominant allele masks the effect of a recessive allele',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A dominant allele is always harmful',
      },
      {
        option: 'A recessive allele is always beneficial',
      },
      {
        option: 'A dominant allele masks the effect of a recessive allele',
      },
      {
        option: 'A recessive allele masks the effect of a dominant allele',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bda691285d655222cb09',
    question: 'What is a gene?',
    correctAnswer: 'A segment of DNA that codes for a specific trait',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A protein that controls cell functions',
      },
      {
        option: 'A segment of DNA that codes for a specific trait',
      },
      {
        option: 'A cell organelle responsible for inheritance',
      },
      {
        option: 'A structure that carries genetic material',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inherite',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bd9a91285d655222cb06',
    question: 'Who is known as the father of genetics?',
    correctAnswer: 'Gregor Mendel',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Charles Darwin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gregor Mendel',
      },
      {
        option: 'James Watson',
      },
      {
        option: 'Francis Crick',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673bd9791285d655222cb03',
    question: 'What is inheritance in genetics?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The process by which genetic information is passed from parents to offspring',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'The process by which genetic information is passed from parents to offspring',
      },
      {
        option: 'The formation of new species',
      },
      {
        option: 'The expression of physical traits',
      },
      {
        option: 'The study of evolutionary relationships',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Inheritance',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b255b660162e545739e2',
    question: 'What is an example of artificial selection?',
    correctAnswer: 'Breeding dogs for specific traits',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Breeding dogs for specific traits',
      },
      {
        option: 'Wolves evolving into dogs',
      },
      {
        option: 'Birds developing different beak shapes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Insects developing resistance to pesticides',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b24db660162e545739df',
    question: 'What is gene flow?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The transfer of genetic material from one population to another',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The random change in allele frequencies in a population',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The transfer of genetic material from one population to another',
      },
      {
        option: 'The formation of new species',
      },
      {
        option: 'The adaptation of species to their environment',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b244b660162e545739dc',
    question: 'Which of the following is an example of convergent evolution?',
    correctAnswer: 'The development of wings in both bats and birds',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The development of wings in both bats and birds',
      },
      {
        option: 'The development of fur in mammals',
      },
      {
        option: 'The development of scales in reptiles',
      },
      {
        option: 'The development of roots in plants',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b23cb660162e545739d9',
    question: 'What is the Hardy-Weinberg principle used for?',
    correctAnswer: 'To predict allele frequencies in a non-evolving population',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To predict allele frequencies in a non-evolving population',
      },
      {
        option: 'To measure genetic mutation rates',
      },
      {
        option: 'To calculate population growth',
      },
      {
        option: 'To determine the age of fossils',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b235b660162e545739d6',
    question: 'Which of the following provides evidence for evolution?',
    correctAnswer: 'Fossil records',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Fossil records',
      },
      {
        option: 'Weather patterns',
      },
      {
        option: 'Plate tectonics',
      },
      {
        option: 'Astronomical observations',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b22eb660162e545739d3',
    question: 'What is the bottleneck effect?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A sharp reduction in the size of a population due to environmental events',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A gradual increase in population size over time',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A sharp reduction in the size of a population due to environmental events',
      },
      {
        option: 'The introduction of new species into an ecosystem',
      },
      {
        option: 'The transfer of genes between populations',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b226b660162e545739d0',
    question:
      'Which term describes a trait that helps an organism survive and reproduce?',
    correctAnswer: 'Adaptation',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Mutation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adaptation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Variation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Selection',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b21eb660162e545739cd',
    question: 'What is speciation?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The formation of new and distinct species in the course of evolution',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The extinction of species',
      },
      {
        option: 'The adaptation of species to their environment',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The formation of new and distinct species in the course of evolution',
      },
      {
        option: 'The migration of species',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b215b660162e545739ca',
    question: 'Which of the following is an example of a homologous structure?',
    correctAnswer: 'The wing of a bat and the arm of a human',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The wing of a bat and the wing of a butterfly',
      },
      {
        option: 'The fin of a fish and the flipper of a dolphin',
      },
      {
        option: 'The wing of a bat and the arm of a human',
      },
      {
        option: 'The beak of a bird and the snout of a dog',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b202b660162e545739c7',
    question: 'What is genetic drift?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A change in the frequency of alleles due to random sampling',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A change in the frequency of alleles due to natural selection',
      },
      {
        option: 'A change in the frequency of alleles due to mutation',
      },
      {
        option: 'A change in the frequency of alleles due to random sampling',
      },
      {
        option: 'A change in the frequency of alleles due to gene flow',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1fab660162e545739c4',
    question: "What does the term 'fitness' refer to in evolutionary biology?",
    correctAnswer: 'The ability to survive and reproduce',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The physical strength of an organism',
      },
      {
        option: 'The ability to survive and reproduce',
      },
      {
        option: 'The speed of an organism',
      },
      {
        option: 'The lifespan of an organism',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1f1b660162e545739c1',
    question:
      'What is the term for a change in the genetic composition of a population over time?',
    correctAnswer: 'Evolution',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Evolution',
      },
      {
        option: 'Adaptation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Speciation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Natural selection',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1e7b660162e545739be',
    question:
      'Which book did Charles Darwin write to present his theory of evolution?',
    correctAnswer: 'On the Origin of Species',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The Descent of Man',
      },
      {
        option: 'On the Origin of Species',
      },
      {
        option: 'Principles of Geology',
      },
      {
        option: 'The Voyage of the Beagle',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1dfb660162e545739bb',
    question: 'Who is known as the father of evolution?',
    correctAnswer: 'Charles Darwin',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Gregor Mendel',
      },
      {
        option: 'Charles Darwin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Jean-Baptiste Lamarck',
      },
      {
        option: 'Alfred Wallace',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1d8b660162e545739b8',
    question: 'What is the primary mechanism by which evolution occurs?',
    correctAnswer: 'Natural selection',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Natural selection',
      },
      {
        option: 'Genetic drift',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mutation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gene flow',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Evolution',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1b4b660162e545739b5',
    question:
      'Which type of biotechnology involves the use of living organisms to degrade environmental pollutants?',
    correctAnswer: 'Bioremediation',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Bioinformatics',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bioremediation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bioengineering',
      },
      {
        option: 'Biofuels',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1abb660162e545739b2',
    question: 'What is the Human Genome Project?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A project aimed at mapping all the genes in the human genome',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A project aimed at mapping all the genes in the human genome',
      },
      {
        option: 'A project aimed at curing all genetic diseases',
      },
      {
        option: 'A project aimed at creating synthetic life',
      },
      {
        option: 'A project aimed at cloning humans',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b1a2b660162e545739af',
    question:
      'Which of the following is used to introduce foreign DNA into plant cells?',
    correctAnswer: 'Agrobacterium tumefaciens',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'E. coli',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bacillus thuringiensis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Agrobacterium tumefaciens',
      },
      {
        option: 'Saccharomyces cerevisiae',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b197b660162e545739ac',
    question: 'What is a transgenic organism?',
    correctAnswer:
      'An organism that has been genetically modified to contain genes from another species',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'An organism that has been genetically modified to contain genes from another species',
      },
      {
        option: 'An organism that has been cloned',
      },
      {
        option: 'An organism that has been selectively bred',
      },
      {
        option: 'An organism that has been naturally mutated',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b190b660162e545739a9',
    question: 'What is the CRISPR-Cas9 system used for?',
    correctAnswer: 'Gene editing',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Gene sequencing',
      },
      {
        option: 'Protein synthesis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gene editing',
      },
      {
        option: 'RNA interference',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b189b660162e545739a6',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a benefit of genetically modified (GM) crops?',
    correctAnswer: 'Increased resistance to pests',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Increased water usage',
      },
      {
        option: 'Increased resistance to pests',
      },
      {
        option: 'Decreased nutritional value',
      },
      {
        option: 'Reduced yield',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b182b660162e545739a3',
    question: 'What is gene therapy?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A technique for correcting defective genes responsible for disease development',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A technique for selecting desired traits in plants',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A technique for correcting defective genes responsible for disease development',
      },
      {
        option: 'A method for cloning organisms',
      },
      {
        option: 'A process for sequencing DNA',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b17cb660162e545739a0',
    question:
      'Which of the following is an example of a biopharmaceutical product?',
    correctAnswer: 'Insulin',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Insulin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Aspirin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Penicillin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Paracetamol',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b172b660162e5457399d',
    question: 'What is the purpose of gel electrophoresis in biotechnology?',
    correctAnswer: 'To separate DNA fragments based on their size',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To separate DNA fragments based on their size',
      },
      {
        option: 'To amplify DNA',
      },
      {
        option: 'To cut DNA at specific sequences',
      },
      {
        option: 'To transfer genes into organisms',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b16bb660162e5457399a',
    question: 'What is the Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) used for?',
    correctAnswer: 'To amplify small segments of DNA',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To amplify small segments of DNA',
      },
      {
        option: 'To sequence DNA',
      },
      {
        option: 'To edit genes',
      },
      {
        option: 'To clone organisms',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b163b660162e54573997',
    question: 'Which enzyme is commonly used to cut DNA at specific sequences?',
    correctAnswer: 'Restriction enzyme',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'DNA polymerase',
      },
      {
        option: 'Restriction enzyme',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ligase',
      },
      {
        option: 'Reverse transcriptase',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b15cb660162e54573994',
    question: 'What is the role of plasmids in genetic engineering?',
    correctAnswer: 'They are used as vectors to transfer genes into bacteria',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'They act as enzymes to cut DNA',
      },
      {
        option: 'They are used as vectors to transfer genes into bacteria',
      },
      {
        option: 'They produce energy for the cell',
      },
      {
        option: 'They are used to measure gene expression',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b155b660162e54573991',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a common application of biotechnology in agriculture?',
    correctAnswer: 'Genetically modified crops',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Antibiotic production',
      },
      {
        option: 'Genetically modified crops',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vaccine development',
      },
      {
        option: 'DNA fingerprinting',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b14eb660162e5457398e',
    question: 'What is recombinant DNA technology?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A technique used to join together DNA from different sources',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A process of selecting desired traits in organisms',
      },
      {
        option: 'A technique used to join together DNA from different sources',
      },
      {
        option: 'A method for studying the structure of proteins',
      },
      {
        option: 'A way to measure enzyme activity',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b147b660162e5457398b',
    question: 'What is the primary goal of biotechnology?',
    correctAnswer:
      'To use living organisms or their products to improve human health and the environment',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To study the universe',
      },
      {
        option:
          'To use living organisms or their products to improve human health and the environment',
      },
      {
        option: 'To create new chemical compounds',
      },
      {
        option: 'To explore space',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Biotechnology',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b10cb660162e54573988',
    question:
      'What type of joint is found in the elbows and knees, allowing for movement in one plane?',
    correctAnswer: 'Hinge joint',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ball and socket joint',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hinge joint',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pivot joint',
      },
      {
        option: 'Saddle joint',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b102b660162e54573985',
    question: 'What is the functional unit of a muscle fiber called?',
    correctAnswer: 'Sarcomere',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Myofibril',
      },
      {
        option: 'Sarcomere',
      },
      {
        option: 'Myosin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Actin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0f8b660162e54573982',
    question:
      'Which protein is the main component of the thick filaments in muscle fibers?',
    correctAnswer: 'Myosin',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Actin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Myosin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tropomyosin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Troponin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0f0b660162e5457397f',
    question:
      'Which disease is characterized by the weakening of bones due to the loss of bone density?',
    correctAnswer: 'Osteoporosis',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Arthritis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Osteoporosis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Scoliosis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Rickets',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0e9b660162e5457397c',
    question: 'What is the function of red bone marrow?',
    correctAnswer: 'To produce blood cells',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To store fat',
      },
      {
        option: 'To produce blood cells',
      },
      {
        option: 'To store calcium',
      },
      {
        option: 'To produce hormones',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0e0b660162e54573979',
    question:
      'What structure in the human body acts as a cushion between bones at a joint?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cartilage',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ligaments',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tendons',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cartilage',
      },
      {
        option: 'Bursa',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0d8b660162e54573976',
    question: 'Which type of muscle is under voluntary control?',
    correctAnswer: 'Skeletal muscle',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Skeletal muscle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Smooth muscle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cardiac muscle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Involuntary muscle',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0cfb660162e54573973',
    question:
      'What is the primary component of bone that makes it hard and strong?',
    correctAnswer: 'Calcium phosphate',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Collagen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Calcium phosphate',
      },
      {
        option: 'Keratin',
      },
      {
        option: 'Elastin',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0c6b660162e54573970',
    question: 'What is the role of ligaments in the skeletal system?',
    correctAnswer: 'To connect bones to other bones',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To connect muscles to bones',
      },
      {
        option: 'To cushion joints',
      },
      {
        option: 'To connect bones to other bones',
      },
      {
        option: 'To produce red blood cells',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0bfb660162e5457396d',
    question:
      'What type of joint is found in the shoulder and hip, allowing for a wide range of motion?',
    correctAnswer: 'Ball and socket joint',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Hinge joint',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pivot joint',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ball and socket joint',
      },
      {
        option: 'Gliding joint',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0b8b660162e5457396a',
    question:
      'Which part of the skeleton includes the skull, vertebral column, and rib cage?',
    correctAnswer: 'Axial skeleton',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Appendicular skeleton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Axial skeleton',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pectoral girdle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pelvic girdle',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0b0b660162e54573967',
    question: 'What connects muscles to bones?',
    correctAnswer: 'Tendons',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Ligaments',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cartilage',
      },
      {
        option: 'Tendons',
      },
      {
        option: 'Joints',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0a9b660162e54573964',
    question: 'Which type of muscle is found in the heart?',
    correctAnswer: 'Cardiac muscle',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Skeletal muscle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Smooth muscle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Cardiac muscle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Striated muscle',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b0a0b660162e54573961',
    question: 'What is the primary function of the skeletal system?',
    correctAnswer: 'To provide support and structure to the body',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To facilitate gas exchange',
      },
      {
        option: 'To circulate blood',
      },
      {
        option: 'To provide support and structure to the body',
      },
      {
        option: 'To produce hormones',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b087b660162e5457395e',
    question:
      'What type of tissue is primarily responsible for movement in the human body?',
    correctAnswer: 'Muscle tissue',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Epithelial tissue',
      },
      {
        option: 'Connective tissue',
      },
      {
        option: 'Muscle tissue',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nervous tissue',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Support and Movement',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b024b660162e5457395b',
    question:
      'What is the main difference between aerobic and anaerobic respiration?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Aerobic respiration requires oxygen, whereas anaerobic respiration does not',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'Aerobic respiration produces less ATP than anaerobic respiration',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Aerobic respiration requires oxygen, whereas anaerobic respiration does not',
      },
      {
        option: 'Anaerobic respiration occurs in the mitochondria',
      },
      {
        option: 'Aerobic respiration produces alcohol as a byproduct',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b01cb660162e54573958',
    question: 'What happens to pyruvate in the absence of oxygen?',
    correctAnswer: 'It undergoes fermentation',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It enters the Krebs cycle',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is converted into glucose',
      },
      {
        option: 'It undergoes fermentation',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is stored as glycogen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b014b660162e54573955',
    question: 'What is the primary purpose of oxygen in cellular respiration?',
    correctAnswer:
      'To act as the final electron acceptor in the electron transport chain',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To produce ATP directly',
      },
      {
        option:
          'To act as the final electron acceptor in the electron transport chain',
      },
      {
        option: 'To break down glucose',
      },
      {
        option: 'To transport electrons',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b00cb660162e54573952',
    question:
      'What molecule carries electrons from the Krebs cycle to the electron transport chain?',
    correctAnswer: 'NADH',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ATP',
      },
      {
        option: 'NADH',
      },
      {
        option: 'FADH2',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glucose',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673b003b660162e5457394f',
    question:
      'Which of the following processes occurs in the cytoplasm of the cell?',
    correctAnswer: 'Glycolysis',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Krebs cycle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electron transport chain',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glycolysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxidative phosphorylation',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673affbb660162e5457394c',
    question: 'What is anaerobic respiration?',
    correctAnswer: 'Respiration without oxygen',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Respiration with oxygen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Respiration without oxygen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Respiration in plants',
      },
      {
        option: 'Respiration in animals',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aff3b660162e54573949',
    question: 'Which stage of cellular respiration generates the most ATP?',
    correctAnswer: 'Electron transport chain',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Glycolysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Krebs cycle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electron transport chain',
      },
      {
        option: 'Fermentation',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afe9b660162e54573946',
    question:
      'How many ATP molecules are produced from one molecule of glucose during aerobic respiration?',
    correctAnswer: '36-38',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '2',
      },
      {
        option: '4',
      },
      {
        option: '36-38',
      },
      {
        option: '40',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afe0b660162e54573943',
    question: 'Which gas is a byproduct of cellular respiration?',
    correctAnswer: 'Carbon dioxide',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Oxygen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nitrogen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Carbon dioxide',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hydrogen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afd9b660162e54573940',
    question: 'Where does the Krebs cycle take place within the cell?',
    correctAnswer: 'Mitochondria',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Cytoplasm',
      },
      {
        option: 'Mitochondria',
      },
      {
        option: 'Nucleus',
      },
      {
        option: 'Ribosomes',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afd1b660162e5457393d',
    question: 'What is the end product of glycolysis?',
    correctAnswer: 'Pyruvate',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ATP',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glucose',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxygen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pyruvate',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afc9b660162e5457393a',
    question:
      'Which of the following is the correct sequence of events in cellular respiration?',
    correctAnswer: 'Glycolysis -> Krebs cycle -> Electron transport chain',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Krebs cycle -> Glycolysis -> Electron transport chain',
      },
      {
        option: 'Electron transport chain -> Krebs cycle -> Glycolysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glycolysis -> Krebs cycle -> Electron transport chain',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glycolysis -> Electron transport chain -> Krebs cycle',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afc1b660162e54573937',
    question:
      'What molecule is the final electron acceptor in the electron transport chain during aerobic respiration?',
    correctAnswer: 'Oxygen',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Carbon dioxide',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oxygen',
      },
      {
        option: 'Water',
      },
      {
        option: 'Glucose',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afb9b660162e54573934',
    question:
      'Which organ is primarily responsible for gas exchange in humans?',
    correctAnswer: 'Lungs',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Liver',
      },
      {
        option: 'Heart',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lungs',
      },
      {
        option: 'Kidneys',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673afb2b660162e54573931',
    question: 'What is the primary purpose of respiration in living organisms?',
    correctAnswer: 'To produce energy',
    class: 'Biology',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To produce energy',
      },
      {
        option: 'To remove waste',
      },
      {
        option: 'To circulate blood',
      },
      {
        option: 'To transport oxygen',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Respiration',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af52b660162e5457392e',
    question: 'Which function is used to write a single character to a file?',
    correctAnswer: 'put()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'write()',
      },
      {
        option: 'put()',
      },
      {
        option: 'insert()',
      },
      {
        option: 'send()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af4bb660162e5457392b',
    question: 'What is the purpose of the ios::ate mode when opening a file?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Opens the file and moves the control to the end of the file',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Opens the file and moves the control to the end of the file',
      },
      {
        option: 'Opens the file for appending',
      },
      {
        option: 'Truncates the file to zero length',
      },
      {
        option: 'Opens the file in binary mode',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af40b660162e54573928',
    question:
      'Which member function of ifstream is used to move the file pointer to a specific location?',
    correctAnswer: 'seekg()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'seekp()',
      },
      {
        option: 'seekg()',
      },
      {
        option: 'moveg()',
      },
      {
        option: 'setg()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af38b660162e54573925',
    question: 'What does the ios::trunc mode do when opening a file?',
    correctAnswer: 'Truncates the file to zero length if it already exists',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Opens the file for reading',
      },
      {
        option: 'Appends all output to the end of the file',
      },
      {
        option: 'Truncates the file to zero length if it already exists',
      },
      {
        option: 'Opens the file in binary mode',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af30b660162e54573922',
    question: 'Which ios mode flag is used to open a file in binary mode?',
    correctAnswer: 'ios::binary',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ios::bin',
      },
      {
        option: 'ios::binary',
      },
      {
        option: 'ios::b',
      },
      {
        option: 'ios::binary_mode',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af27b660162e5457391f',
    question:
      'Which of the following is the correct way to close a file in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'file.close();',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'file.close();',
      },
      {
        option: 'file.end();',
      },
      {
        option: 'file.shutdown();',
      },
      {
        option: 'file.stop();',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af1eb660162e5457391c',
    question: 'What does the ios::app mode do when opening a file?',
    correctAnswer: 'Appends all output to the end of the file',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Appends all output to the end of the file',
      },
      {
        option: 'Truncates the file to zero length',
      },
      {
        option: 'Opens the file for reading',
      },
      {
        option: 'Opens the file in binary mode',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af17b660162e54573919',
    question: 'How do you check if a file is successfully opened in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'file.is_open()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'file.exists()',
      },
      {
        option: 'file.opened()',
      },
      {
        option: 'file.is_open()',
      },
      {
        option: 'file.good()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af0fb660162e54573916',
    question: 'Which function is used to read data from a file in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'read()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'read()',
      },
      {
        option: 'get()',
      },
      {
        option: 'receive()',
      },
      {
        option: 'extract()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af07b660162e54573913',
    question: 'Which function is used to write data to a file in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'write()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'write()',
      },
      {
        option: 'put()',
      },
      {
        option: 'send()',
      },
      {
        option: 'insert()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673af00b660162e54573910',
    question:
      "How do you open a file named 'example.txt' in read mode using ifstream?",
    correctAnswer: 'ifstream file("example.txt");',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ifstream file = "example.txt";',
      },
      {
        option: 'ifstream file("example.txt");',
      },
      {
        option: 'ifstream file.read("example.txt");',
      },
      {
        option: 'ifstream file.open("example.txt");',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aef8b660162e5457390d',
    question:
      'Which class is used for both input and output file operations in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'fstream',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ifstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'ofstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'fstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'iostream',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aef0b660162e5457390a',
    question:
      'Which of the following is used to create an input file stream in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'ifstream',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ofstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'ifstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'fstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'filebuf',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aee7b660162e54573907',
    question:
      'Which of the following is used to create an output file stream in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'ofstream',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ifstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'ofstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'fstream',
      },
      {
        option: 'filebuf',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aee0b660162e54573904',
    question: 'Which header file is required for file handling in C++?',
    correctAnswer: '<fstream>',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '<fstream>',
      },
      {
        option: '<file>',
      },
      {
        option: '<iostream>',
      },
      {
        option: '<fstream.h>',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'File Handling',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aebbb660162e54573901',
    question:
      'Which of the following statements is correct about static members in a class?',
    correctAnswer: 'Static members are shared by all objects of the class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Static members can only be accessed by static functions',
      },
      {
        option: 'Static members are unique to each object',
      },
      {
        option: 'Static members are shared by all objects of the class',
      },
      {
        option: 'Static members cannot be modified',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aeb3b660162e545738fe',
    question:
      "Which of the following statements is true about the 'const' keyword in member functions?",
    correctAnswer:
      'It indicates that the member function does not modify the object',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'It indicates that the member function does not modify the object',
      },
      {
        option: 'It makes the member function constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'It makes the member function static',
      },
      {
        option: 'It makes the member function public',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aeaab660162e545738fb',
    question: 'How do you declare a friend function in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'Using the keyword friend',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Using the keyword friend',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using the keyword public',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using the keyword private',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using the keyword protected',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673aea2b660162e545738f8',
    question: 'Which keyword is used to inherit a class in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'public',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'inherits',
      },
      {
        option: 'extends',
      },
      {
        option: 'public',
      },
      {
        option: 'base',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae9ab660162e545738f5',
    question: 'What is encapsulation in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Binding data and functions into a single unit called a class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Binding data and functions into a single unit called a class',
      },
      {
        option: 'Deriving new classes from existing classes',
      },
      {
        option: 'Writing functions with the same name but different parameters',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hiding implementation details from the user',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae92b660162e545738f2',
    question: 'Which function is called when an object is copied?',
    correctAnswer: 'Copy constructor',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Copy constructor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Default constructor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Move constructor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Assignment operator',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae8bb660162e545738ef',
    question:
      'Which access specifier makes class members accessible only within the same class?',
    correctAnswer: 'private',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'public',
      },
      {
        option: 'private',
      },
      {
        option: 'protected',
      },
      {
        option: 'default',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae82b660162e545738ec',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a special function that is called when a new object is created?',
    correctAnswer: 'Constructor',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Destructor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Constructor',
      },
      {
        option: 'Copy function',
      },
      {
        option: 'Main function',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae73b660162e545738e8',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a valid way to declare an object of class MyClass?',
    correctAnswer: 'MyClass obj;',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'MyClass obj();',
      },
      {
        option: 'class obj;',
      },
      {
        option: 'MyClass obj;',
      },
      {
        option: 'obj MyClass;',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae6bb660162e545738e5',
    question: 'What is a destructor in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A member function that is invoked when an object is destroyed',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A member function that is invoked when an object is created',
      },
      {
        option: 'A member function that is invoked when an object is copied',
      },
      {
        option: 'A member function that is invoked when an object is destroyed',
      },
      {
        option: 'A member function that is invoked when an object is moved',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae5eb660162e545738e2',
    question: 'Which of the following is true about constructors in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'They are called automatically when an object is created',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'They can have any name',
      },
      {
        option: 'They are called automatically when an object is created',
      },
      {
        option: 'They can return values',
      },
      {
        option: 'They are used to delete objects',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae56b660162e545738df',
    question:
      'How do you define a member function outside the class definition?',
    correctAnswer: 'Using the scope resolution operator ::',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Using the dot operator .',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using the arrow operator ->',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using the scope resolution operator ::',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using the comma operator ,',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae4fb660162e545738dc',
    question: 'What is an object in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'An instance of a class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A blueprint for a class',
      },
      {
        option: 'An instance of a class',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function',
      },
      {
        option: 'A variable',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae48b660162e545738d9',
    question: 'Which keyword is used to define a class in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'class',
      },
      {
        option: 'struct',
      },
      {
        option: 'object',
      },
      {
        option: 'define',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Objects and Classes',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae1cb660162e545738d6',
    question:
      'Which of the following statements is true about references and pointers?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A reference must be initialized when declared, but a pointer can be declared without initialization',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'References and pointers are the same in C++',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A reference must be initialized when declared, but a pointer can be declared without initialization',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A pointer must be initialized when declared, but a reference can be declared without initialization',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Neither pointers nor references need to be initialized when declared',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae15b660162e545738d3',
    question:
      'What will be the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nint x = 5;\nint *ptr = &x;\n*ptr = 10;\nstd::cout << x;\n```',
    correctAnswer: '10',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '5',
      },
      {
        option: '10',
      },
      {
        option: 'The address of x',
      },
      {
        option: 'ptr',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae0db660162e545738d0',
    question:
      'Which of the following is used to declare a pointer to a pointer in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'int **ptr;',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int *ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'int **ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'int &ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'int ptr**;',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ae05b660162e545738cd',
    question: "What is the use of the 'nullptr' keyword in C++?",
    correctAnswer: 'It represents a null pointer constant',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It represents a null pointer constant',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is used to dereference a pointer',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is used to allocate memory dynamically',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is used to access the address of a variable',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adfab660162e545738ca',
    question:
      'Which of the following statements is true about pointer arithmetic?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Incrementing a pointer increases its value by the size of the data type it points to',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Pointers cannot be incremented',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Incrementing a pointer increases its value by the size of the data type it points to',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Incrementing a pointer decreases its value by the size of the data type it points to',
      },
      {
        option: 'Pointers can only be incremented by 1',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adf3b660162e545738c7',
    question:
      'What will be the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nint x = 5;\nint *ptr = &x;\nstd::cout << *ptr;\n```',
    correctAnswer: '5',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The address of x',
      },
      {
        option: 'x',
      },
      {
        option: '5',
      },
      {
        option: 'ptr',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adeab660162e545738c4',
    question:
      'Which of the following deletes the memory allocated to a pointer named ptr in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'delete ptr;',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'free(ptr);',
      },
      {
        option: 'delete ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'remove ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'deallocate ptr;',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673addeb660162e545738c1',
    question: 'What is a dangling pointer in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A pointer pointing to a memory location that has been freed',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A pointer that has not been initialized',
      },
      {
        option: 'A pointer pointing to a memory location that has been freed',
      },
      {
        option: 'A pointer that points to an invalid memory address',
      },
      {
        option: 'A pointer that is used before declaration',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673add5b660162e545738be',
    question:
      'What is the correct way to dynamically allocate memory for an array of 10 integers in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'int *arr = new int[10];',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int *arr = new int(10);',
      },
      {
        option: 'int *arr = new int[10];',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr = new int[10];',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr[10] = new int;',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adcdb660162e545738bb',
    question: 'How do you access the value pointed to by a pointer named ptr?',
    correctAnswer: '*ptr',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ptr',
      },
      {
        option: '*ptr',
      },
      {
        option: '&ptr',
      },
      {
        option: 'ptr*',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adc5b660162e545738b8',
    question:
      'What does the following code do?\n\n```cpp\nint x = 10;\nint *ptr = &x;\n```',
    correctAnswer: 'Declares a pointer ptr and assigns it the address of x',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Declares an integer variable and a pointer variable',
      },
      {
        option: 'Declares a pointer ptr and assigns it the address of x',
      },
      {
        option: 'Declares a pointer ptr and assigns it the value of x',
      },
      {
        option: 'Declares an integer variable and assigns it the address of x',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adbeb660162e545738b5',
    question: 'How do you declare a pointer to an integer in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'int *ptr;',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'int *ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'int &ptr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'pointer int *ptr;',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adb4b660162e545738b2',
    question:
      'Which operator is used to access the value at the address stored in a pointer?',
    correctAnswer: '*',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '*',
      },
      {
        option: '&',
      },
      {
        option: '->',
      },
      {
        option: '@',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673adacb660162e545738af',
    question: 'Which operator is used to get the address of a variable in C++?',
    correctAnswer: '&',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '*',
      },
      {
        option: '&',
      },
      {
        option: '&&',
      },
      {
        option: '@',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ada4b660162e545738ac',
    question: 'What is a pointer in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A variable that stores the memory address of another variable',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A variable that stores data',
      },
      {
        option: 'A variable that stores the memory address of another variable',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function that returns an address',
      },
      {
        option: 'A keyword for memory allocation',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Pointers',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad6eb660162e545738a9',
    question: 'Which function allows dynamic memory allocation in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'new',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'malloc',
      },
      {
        option: 'alloc',
      },
      {
        option: 'new',
      },
      {
        option: 'create',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad67b660162e545738a6',
    question:
      'Which of the following is the correct syntax to define a function that takes no parameters and returns an integer?',
    correctAnswer: 'int func();',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int func();',
      },
      {
        option: 'int func(void);',
      },
      {
        option: 'void func();',
      },
      {
        option: 'func int();',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad5fb660162e545738a3',
    question: 'What is a pure virtual function in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A function declared in a base class that has no definition relative to the base class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A function with no return type',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A function declared in a base class that has no definition relative to the base class',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function that must be defined in all derived classes',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function that returns void',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad57b660162e545738a0',
    question:
      'Which of the following can be used to specify default arguments in a function?',
    correctAnswer: 'In the function prototype or definition',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'In the function call',
      },
      {
        option: 'In the function prototype or definition',
      },
      {
        option: 'In the main function',
      },
      {
        option: 'In a header file',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad4fb660162e5457389d',
    question: 'What is recursion in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'A function calling itself',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A function that is not called',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function that returns multiple values',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function calling itself',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function that does not return a value',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad45b660162e5457389a',
    question: 'What does the inline keyword indicate in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'The function should be expanded inline where it is invoked',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The function should be expanded inline where it is invoked',
      },
      {
        option: 'The function is a template',
      },
      {
        option: 'The function is static',
      },
      {
        option: 'The function does not return a value',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad3eb660162e54573897',
    question:
      'Which of the following functions is used to swap the values of two variables?',
    correctAnswer: 'std::swap()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'std::swap()',
      },
      {
        option: 'std::exchange()',
      },
      {
        option: 'std::change()',
      },
      {
        option: 'std::alter()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad32b660162e54573894',
    question:
      'What will be the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nvoid func() {\n  std::cout << "Hello";\n}\nint main() {\n  func();\n  return 0;\n}\n```',
    correctAnswer: 'Hello',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'func',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hello',
      },
      {
        option: 'main',
      },
      {
        option: '0',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad2ab660162e54573891',
    question: 'Which of the following is true about function overloading?',
    correctAnswer: 'Functions with the same name but different parameters',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Functions with the same name but different return types',
      },
      {
        option: 'Functions with the same name but different parameters',
      },
      {
        option: 'Functions with different names but the same parameters',
      },
      {
        option: 'Functions with different names but the same return type',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad21b660162e5457388e',
    question: 'Which keyword is used to return a value from a function?',
    correctAnswer: 'return',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'return',
      },
      {
        option: 'exit',
      },
      {
        option: 'break',
      },
      {
        option: 'continue',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad19b660162e5457388b',
    question: 'What is a function prototype in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      "A declaration of a function that specifies the function's name, return type, and parameters",
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "A definition of a function that includes the function's code",
      },
      {
        option:
          "A declaration of a function that specifies the function's name, return type, and parameters",
      },
      {
        option: 'A template of a function',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function call',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad11b660162e54573888',
    question:
      'Which of the following is not a valid return type for a function in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'var',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int',
      },
      {
        option: 'float',
      },
      {
        option: 'void',
      },
      {
        option: 'var',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad0ab660162e54573885',
    question:
      'Which of the following is the correct way to declare a function that returns an integer and takes two integer arguments?',
    correctAnswer: 'int func(int a, int b);',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int func(int a, int b);',
      },
      {
        option: 'func int(int a, int b);',
      },
      {
        option: 'int func(a, b);',
      },
      {
        option: 'int func(int, int);',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ad00b660162e54573882',
    question:
      'What is the default return type of a function in C++ if none is specified?',
    correctAnswer: 'int',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'void',
      },
      {
        option: 'int',
      },
      {
        option: 'float',
      },
      {
        option: 'double',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673acf9b660162e5457387f',
    question: 'Which keyword is used to define a function in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'void',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'func',
      },
      {
        option: 'void',
      },
      {
        option: 'function',
      },
      {
        option: 'define',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Functions',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac92b660162e5457387c',
    question:
      'What will be the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nstd::string str = "Hello";\nstd::cout << str.length();\n```',
    correctAnswer: '5',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '4',
      },
      {
        option: '5',
      },
      {
        option: '6',
      },
      {
        option: '7',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac8ab660162e54573879',
    question: 'Which function is used to compare two C-style strings?',
    correctAnswer: 'strcmp()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'strcomp()',
      },
      {
        option: 'strcompare()',
      },
      {
        option: 'strcmp()',
      },
      {
        option: 'strcompare()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac81b660162e54573876',
    question:
      'Which of the following correctly declares a string in C++ using the string class?',
    correctAnswer: 'std::string str = "Hello";',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'std::string str = "Hello";',
      },
      {
        option: 'char str = "Hello";',
      },
      {
        option: "string str = 'Hello';",
      },
      {
        option: 'string str = Hello;',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac77b660162e54573873',
    question:
      "How do you access the last element of an array 'arr' with 'n' elements?",
    correctAnswer: 'arr[n-1]',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'arr[n]',
      },
      {
        option: 'arr[n-1]',
      },
      {
        option: 'arr[n+1]',
      },
      {
        option: 'arr[n-2]',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac61b660162e54573870',
    question: 'Which of the following statements is true about arrays in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'Arrays are of fixed size',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Arrays are dynamic in size',
      },
      {
        option: 'Arrays can store different types of data',
      },
      {
        option: 'Arrays are of fixed size',
      },
      {
        option: 'Array size can be changed after declaration',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac59b660162e5457386d',
    question:
      'How do you initialize an array of 5 integers with all elements set to 0?',
    correctAnswer: 'int arr[5] = {0};',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int arr[5] = {0};',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr[5] = {0,0,0,0,0};',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr[5];',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr[] = {0};',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac50b660162e5457386a',
    question:
      'Which of the following functions can be used to concatenate two C-style strings?',
    correctAnswer: 'strcat()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'strcat()',
      },
      {
        option: 'strcombine()',
      },
      {
        option: 'stradd()',
      },
      {
        option: 'strmerge()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac47b660162e54573867',
    question:
      'What will be the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nint arr[] = {1, 2, 3, 4, 5};\nstd::cout << arr[2];\n```',
    correctAnswer: '3',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '1',
      },
      {
        option: '2',
      },
      {
        option: '3',
      },
      {
        option: '4',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac3eb660162e54573864',
    question: 'How do you declare a two-dimensional array of integers in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'int arr[3][4];',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int arr[3][4];',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr{3,4};',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr(3,4);',
      },
      {
        option: 'array<int> arr(3,4);',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac33b660162e54573861',
    question: 'Which function is used to find the length of a C-style string?',
    correctAnswer: 'strlen()',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'length()',
      },
      {
        option: 'strlen()',
      },
      {
        option: 'size()',
      },
      {
        option: 'sizeof()',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac2ab660162e5457385e',
    question:
      'What is the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nchar str[] = "Hello, World!";\nstd::cout << str[7];\n```',
    correctAnswer: 'W',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'H',
      },
      {
        option: ',',
      },
      {
        option: 'W',
      },
      {
        option: 'o',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac21b660162e5457385b',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a valid way to declare a C-style string?',
    correctAnswer: 'char str[] = "Hello";',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'char str[] = "Hello";',
      },
      {
        option: 'string str = "Hello";',
      },
      {
        option: "char str = 'Hello';",
      },
      {
        option: 'char str = "Hello";',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac17b660162e54573858',
    question: "How do you access the 5th element in an array named 'arr'?",
    correctAnswer: 'arr[4]',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'arr[5]',
      },
      {
        option: 'arr(5)',
      },
      {
        option: 'arr[4]',
      },
      {
        option: 'arr(4)',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac0db660162e54573855',
    question: 'What is the index of the first element in an array?',
    correctAnswer: '0',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '0',
      },
      {
        option: '1',
      },
      {
        option: '-1',
      },
      {
        option: 'Depends on the array',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '6673ac06b660162e54573852',
    question:
      'Which of the following correctly declares an array of 10 integers in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'int arr[10];',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int arr[10];',
      },
      {
        option: 'int arr;',
      },
      {
        option: 'arr{10};',
      },
      {
        option: 'array int[10];',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Arrays and Strings',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730ce5a2d15d5e01870164',
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the 'else' clause in an if-else statement?",
    correctAnswer: 'To execute a block of code if the condition is false',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To execute a block of code if the condition is true',
      },
      {
        option: 'To terminate the program',
      },
      {
        option: 'To repeat a block of code',
      },
      {
        option: 'To execute a block of code if the condition is false',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730cdea2d15d5e01870161',
    question: "What does the 'default' keyword signify in a switch statement?",
    correctAnswer: 'It specifies the code to run if no case matches',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It specifies the first case',
      },
      {
        option: 'It specifies the last case',
      },
      {
        option: 'It specifies the code to run if no case matches',
      },
      {
        option: 'It specifies the code to run for all cases',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730cd6a2d15d5e0187015e',
    question:
      'Which of the following control structures are used to repeat a block of code?',
    correctAnswer: 'Loops',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Decision-making',
      },
      {
        option: 'Loops',
      },
      {
        option: 'Branching',
      },
      {
        option: 'Functions',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730ccfa2d15d5e0187015b',
    question:
      'What will be the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nint i = 0;\ndo {\n  std::cout << i << " ";\n} while (i++ < 3);\n```',
    correctAnswer: '0 1 2 3',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '0 1 2 3 4',
      },
      {
        option: '0 1 2 3',
      },
      {
        option: '1 2 3 4',
      },
      {
        option: '1 2 3',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730cc7a2d15d5e01870158',
    question:
      'Which of the following can be used to implement a conditional control structure in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'if-else',
      },
      {
        option: 'switch',
      },
      {
        option: 'ternary operator',
      },
      {
        option: 'All of the above',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730cbfa2d15d5e01870155',
    question:
      'Which of the following statements is used to exit from a function in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'return',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'break',
      },
      {
        option: 'continue',
      },
      {
        option: 'exit',
      },
      {
        option: 'return',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730cb7a2d15d5e01870152',
    question:
      'Which control structure is best used when the number of iterations is known beforehand?',
    correctAnswer: 'for',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'while',
      },
      {
        option: 'do-while',
      },
      {
        option: 'for',
      },
      {
        option: 'if-else',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730cada2d15d5e0187014f',
    question:
      'What is the output of the following code?\n\n```cpp\nint x = 10;\nif (x > 5) {\n  x = x + 10;\n} else {\n  x = x - 10;\n}\nstd::cout << x;\n```',
    correctAnswer: '20',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '10',
      },
      {
        option: '0',
      },
      {
        option: '20',
      },
      {
        option: '-10',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730ca5a2d15d5e0187014c',
    question:
      'Which control structure is used to handle multiple selections and enumerations?',
    correctAnswer: 'switch',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'if',
      },
      {
        option: 'switch',
      },
      {
        option: 'for',
      },
      {
        option: 'while',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c9da2d15d5e01870149',
    question: 'Which of the following is not a loop control structure in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'switch',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'for',
      },
      {
        option: 'while',
      },
      {
        option: 'do-while',
      },
      {
        option: 'switch',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c93a2d15d5e01870146',
    question:
      'Which keyword is used to skip the current iteration of a loop and proceed with the next iteration?',
    correctAnswer: 'continue',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'break',
      },
      {
        option: 'continue',
      },
      {
        option: 'exit',
      },
      {
        option: 'return',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c89a2d15d5e01870143',
    question:
      'What will the following code print?\n\n```cpp\nfor (int i = 0; i < 5; i++) {\n  if (i == 3) {\n    continue;\n  }\n  std::cout << i << " ";\n}\n```',
    correctAnswer: '0 1 2 4',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: '0 1 2',
      },
      {
        option: '0 1 2 3 4',
      },
      {
        option: '0 1 2 4',
      },
      {
        option: '1 2 3 4',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c81a2d15d5e01870140',
    question:
      'Which of the following is used to exit a loop immediately in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'break',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'continue',
      },
      {
        option: 'exit',
      },
      {
        option: 'break',
      },
      {
        option: 'return',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c78a2d15d5e0187013d',
    question: 'Which loop structure is guaranteed to execute at least once?',
    correctAnswer: 'do-while',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'for',
      },
      {
        option: 'while',
      },
      {
        option: 'do-while',
      },
      {
        option: 'None of the above',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c6fa2d15d5e0187013a',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a conditional control structure in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'if-else',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'for',
      },
      {
        option: 'while',
      },
      {
        option: 'if-else',
      },
      {
        option: 'do-while',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Control Structure',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c2ca2d15d5e01870137',
    question: 'Which of the following is a feature of encapsulation in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'Combining data and functions into a single unit called a class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Deriving new classes from existing classes',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Combining data and functions into a single unit called a class',
      },
      {
        option: 'Hiding implementation details from the user',
      },
      {
        option: 'Using functions with the same name but different parameters',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c24a2d15d5e01870134',
    question: "What does 'public' keyword signify in C++?",
    correctAnswer: 'Members are accessible from outside the class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Members are accessible from within the class only',
      },
      {
        option: 'Members are accessible from outside the class',
      },
      {
        option: 'Members are accessible from derived classes only',
      },
      {
        option: 'Members are accessible from base classes only',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c1da2d15d5e01870131',
    question: 'Which of the following is a user-defined data type in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'Class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'int',
      },
      {
        option: 'float',
      },
      {
        option: 'double',
      },
      {
        option: 'Class',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c14a2d15d5e0187012e',
    question:
      "Which of the following correctly declares an object of class 'MyClass'?",
    correctAnswer: 'MyClass obj;',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'MyClass obj();',
      },
      {
        option: 'MyClass obj;',
      },
      {
        option: 'class MyClass obj;',
      },
      {
        option: 'obj MyClass;',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c0aa2d15d5e0187012b',
    question:
      'Which of the following operators is used to allocate memory dynamically for an object in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'new',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'malloc',
      },
      {
        option: 'calloc',
      },
      {
        option: 'new',
      },
      {
        option: 'alloc',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730c01a2d15d5e01870128',
    question: "What does the term 'abstraction' refer to in C++?",
    correctAnswer:
      'Hiding the complex implementation details and showing only the necessary features',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Deriving a class from another class',
      },
      {
        option:
          'Hiding the complex implementation details and showing only the necessary features',
      },
      {
        option: 'Binding data and functions together',
      },
      {
        option: 'Creating multiple functions with the same name',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bfaa2d15d5e01870125',
    question:
      'Which keyword in C++ is used to prevent a base class from being inherited?',
    correctAnswer: 'final',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'static',
      },
      {
        option: 'const',
      },
      {
        option: 'virtual',
      },
      {
        option: 'final',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bf0a2d15d5e01870122',
    question:
      'Which C++ feature allows a derived class to provide a specific implementation of a function that is already defined in its base class?',
    correctAnswer: 'Function overriding',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Function overloading',
      },
      {
        option: 'Function overriding',
      },
      {
        option: 'Function templating',
      },
      {
        option: 'Function hiding',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730be8a2d15d5e0187011f',
    question: "What is the purpose of the 'this' pointer in C++?",
    correctAnswer: 'To access the calling object inside a member function',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To reference the parent class',
      },
      {
        option: 'To access the calling object inside a member function',
      },
      {
        option: 'To call another constructor',
      },
      {
        option: 'To return the address of the object',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bdda2d15d5e0187011c',
    question: 'Which of the following best describes a constructor in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'A special member function that initializes objects',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A function that returns an integer value',
      },
      {
        option: 'A special member function that initializes objects',
      },
      {
        option: 'A function that always has void return type',
      },
      {
        option: 'A member function that is called automatically',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bd5a2d15d5e01870119',
    question: 'What is polymorphism in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'The ability of different objects to respond to the same function call',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'The ability of a class to inherit from multiple classes',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The ability of different objects to respond to the same function call',
      },
      {
        option:
          'The ability to write functions with the same name but different implementations',
      },
      {
        option: 'The ability to encapsulate data and functions together',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bcca2d15d5e01870116',
    question:
      'Which of the following access specifiers in C++ restricts access to members to only within the same class?',
    correctAnswer: 'private',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'public',
      },
      {
        option: 'private',
      },
      {
        option: 'protected',
      },
      {
        option: 'default',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bc3a2d15d5e01870113',
    question: 'What is inheritance in C++?',
    correctAnswer:
      'A way to form new classes using classes that have already been defined',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'A function to manage memory',
      },
      {
        option: 'A way to hide data',
      },
      {
        option:
          'A way to form new classes using classes that have already been defined',
      },
      {
        option: 'A method of overloading functions',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bbca2d15d5e01870110',
    question: 'Which C++ keyword is used to define a class?',
    correctAnswer: 'class',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'class',
      },
      {
        option: 'struct',
      },
      {
        option: 'object',
      },
      {
        option: 'define',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730bb5a2d15d5e0187010d',
    question:
      'Which of the following is a key feature of object-oriented programming in C++?',
    correctAnswer: 'Encapsulation',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Encapsulation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Procedural programming',
      },
      {
        option: 'Global variables',
      },
      {
        option: 'Structured programming',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Object oriented programming using C++',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b8ea2d15d5e0187010a',
    question: 'What is the main characteristic of the Agile model in SDLC?',
    correctAnswer: 'Flexibility and iterative development',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Rigid and linear process',
      },
      {
        option: 'Flexibility and iterative development',
      },
      {
        option: 'Focus on documentation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Single phase completion',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b86a2d15d5e01870107',
    question:
      'Which phase of the SDLC involves determining whether the project is feasible?',
    correctAnswer: 'Feasibility Study',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Requirement Analysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Design',
      },
      {
        option: 'Feasibility Study',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testing',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b7ea2d15d5e01870104',
    question: 'Which SDLC model emphasizes risk analysis at every phase?',
    correctAnswer: 'Spiral',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Waterfall',
      },
      {
        option: 'Agile',
      },
      {
        option: 'V-Model',
      },
      {
        option: 'Spiral',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b75a2d15d5e01870101',
    question:
      'In the Agile model, what is the term for a single development cycle?',
    correctAnswer: 'Iteration',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Sprint',
      },
      {
        option: 'Phase',
      },
      {
        option: 'Iteration',
      },
      {
        option: 'Stage',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b6da2d15d5e018700fe',
    question: 'Which of the following is not a commonly used SDLC model?',
    correctAnswer: 'Incremental Model',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Waterfall',
      },
      {
        option: 'Agile',
      },
      {
        option: 'Spiral',
      },
      {
        option: 'Incremental Model',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b64a2d15d5e018700fb',
    question:
      'Which SDLC phase involves creating detailed technical specifications?',
    correctAnswer: 'Design',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Requirement Analysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Design',
      },
      {
        option: 'Implementation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testing',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b5ca2d15d5e018700f8',
    question: "What does the 'V' in V-Model stand for?",
    correctAnswer: 'Verification and Validation',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Verification and Validation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Versioning',
      },
      {
        option: 'Vulnerability',
      },
      {
        option: 'Versatility',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b52a2d15d5e018700f5',
    question:
      'Which SDLC model is most suitable for large, complex, and high-risk projects?',
    correctAnswer: 'Spiral',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Waterfall',
      },
      {
        option: 'Agile',
      },
      {
        option: 'V-Model',
      },
      {
        option: 'Spiral',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b4aa2d15d5e018700f2',
    question:
      'In the Waterfall model, each phase must be completed before the next phase begins. Which of the following is a drawback of this approach?',
    correctAnswer: 'It is difficult to go back to a previous phase',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'It is difficult to go back to a previous phase',
      },
      {
        option: 'It encourages iterative development',
      },
      {
        option: 'It is highly flexible',
      },
      {
        option: 'It requires less documentation',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b40a2d15d5e018700ef',
    question: 'What is the main goal of the maintenance phase in the SDLC?',
    correctAnswer: 'To ensure the system continues to function as required',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To gather requirements',
      },
      {
        option: 'To design the system',
      },
      {
        option: 'To ensure the system continues to function as required',
      },
      {
        option: 'To test the system',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b38a2d15d5e018700ec',
    question:
      'Which phase of the SDLC involves deploying the system to the production environment?',
    correctAnswer: 'Deployment',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Design',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testing',
      },
      {
        option: 'Deployment',
      },
      {
        option: 'Maintenance',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b30a2d15d5e018700e9',
    question:
      'Which SDLC model is known for its flexibility and iterative approach?',
    correctAnswer: 'Agile',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Waterfall',
      },
      {
        option: 'Agile',
      },
      {
        option: 'V-Model',
      },
      {
        option: 'Spiral',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b28a2d15d5e018700e6',
    question: 'What is the primary purpose of the testing phase in the SDLC?',
    correctAnswer: 'To identify and fix defects',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'To gather requirements',
      },
      {
        option: 'To create system design',
      },
      {
        option: 'To identify and fix defects',
      },
      {
        option: 'To deploy the system',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b1fa2d15d5e018700e3',
    question: 'In which phase of the SDLC is the actual code written?',
    correctAnswer: 'Implementation',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Requirement Analysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Design',
      },
      {
        option: 'Implementation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testing',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730b18a2d15d5e018700e0',
    question:
      'Which phase of the SDLC involves gathering and analyzing requirements?',
    correctAnswer: 'Requirement Analysis',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Requirement Analysis',
      },
      {
        option: 'Design',
      },
      {
        option: 'Implementation',
      },
      {
        option: 'Testing',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'System Development Life Cycle',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730aa7a2d15d5e018700dd',
    question:
      "What is a 'bootstrap' program in the context of operating systems?",
    correctAnswer:
      'A program that loads the operating system into memory at startup',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option:
          'A program that loads the operating system into memory at startup',
      },
      {
        option: 'A program that manages hardware devices',
      },
      {
        option: 'A program that manages memory allocation',
      },
      {
        option: 'A program that schedules processes',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a98a2d15d5e018700da',
    question: "In operating systems, what does 'thrashing' refer to?",
    correctAnswer: 'Excessive paging and swapping',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'High CPU utilization',
      },
      {
        option: 'Excessive paging and swapping',
      },
      {
        option: 'Too many processes running',
      },
      {
        option: 'Disk fragmentation',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a7ca2d15d5e018700d7',
    question: 'What is the main advantage of a multi-user operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Multiple users can access the system simultaneously',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Faster processing',
      },
      {
        option: 'Multiple users can access the system simultaneously',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lower cost',
      },
      {
        option: 'Easier to manage',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a74a2d15d5e018700d4',
    question:
      'Which of the following is responsible for handling interrupts in an operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Kernel',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Kernel',
      },
      {
        option: 'Shell',
      },
      {
        option: 'Process Manager',
      },
      {
        option: 'File Manager',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a6ba2d15d5e018700d1',
    question: "In Unix/Linux, what does the command 'pwd' do?",
    correctAnswer: 'Prints the current working directory',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Prints the current working directory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Changes the current directory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Deletes a directory',
      },
      {
        option: 'Lists files in a directory',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a62a2d15d5e018700ce',
    question:
      'Which scheduling algorithm assigns the CPU to the process that requests it first?',
    correctAnswer: 'First-Come, First-Served',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Round Robin',
      },
      {
        option: 'First-Come, First-Served',
      },
      {
        option: 'Shortest Job Next',
      },
      {
        option: 'Priority Scheduling',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a57a2d15d5e018700cb',
    question:
      'Which command is used to list files and directories in Unix/Linux?',
    correctAnswer: 'ls',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'ls',
      },
      {
        option: 'dir',
      },
      {
        option: 'list',
      },
      {
        option: 'show',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a4ca2d15d5e018700c8',
    question:
      "What is the main purpose of an operating system's memory management module?",
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: "To manage the system's memory hierarchy",
      },
      {
        option: 'To allocate and deallocate memory to processes',
      },
      {
        option: 'To protect memory space',
      },
      {
        option: 'All of the above',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a43a2d15d5e018700c5',
    question:
      'In a multitasking operating system, what is the technique of CPU switching between different processes called?',
    correctAnswer: 'Context Switching',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Process Scheduling',
      },
      {
        option: 'Time-sharing',
      },
      {
        option: 'Multi-threading',
      },
      {
        option: 'Context Switching',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a39a2d15d5e018700c2',
    question:
      'Which of the following is an example of an open-source operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Linux',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Windows',
      },
      {
        option: 'macOS',
      },
      {
        option: 'Linux',
      },
      {
        option: 'DOS',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a2ca2d15d5e018700bf',
    question: 'What does GUI stand for in the context of operating systems?',
    correctAnswer: 'Graphical User Interface',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'General User Interaction',
      },
      {
        option: 'Graphical User Interface',
      },
      {
        option: 'Graphical Universal Interface',
      },
      {
        option: 'General User Interface',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a20a2d15d5e018700bc',
    question:
      'Which part of the operating system manages the execution of applications?',
    correctAnswer: 'Kernel',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Kernel',
      },
      {
        option: 'Shell',
      },
      {
        option: 'Interface',
      },
      {
        option: 'Device Manager',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a16a2d15d5e018700b9',
    question: 'Which of the following is a real-time operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'RTOS',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Windows XP',
      },
      {
        option: 'Windows 10',
      },
      {
        option: 'RTOS',
      },
      {
        option: 'UNIX',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '66730a0ca2d15d5e018700b6',
    question: 'Which of the following is not an operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'Oracle',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Windows',
      },
      {
        option: 'Linux',
      },
      {
        option: 'Oracle',
      },
      {
        option: 'Android',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
  {
    _id: '667309fca2d15d5e018700b3',
    question: 'What is the function of an operating system?',
    correctAnswer: 'All of the above',
    class: 'Computer',
    fieldsData: [
      {
        option: 'Manages hardware resources',
      },
      {
        option: 'Provides user interface',
      },
      {
        option: 'Manages files and directories',
      },
      {
        option: 'All of the above',
      },
    ],
    chapter: 'Operating system',
    date: '01-05-2024',
    __v: 0,
  },
];
const nineScienceQuestion = [{}];
const nineArtsQuestion = [{}];
const tenthArtsQuestion = [{}];
const tenthScienceQuestion = [{}];

export {
  QuestionData,
  firstYear,
  secondYear,
  nineScienceQuestion,
  nineArtsQuestion,
  tenthArtsQuestion,
  tenthScienceQuestion,
};
